<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667919">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:13:01</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:21</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667919.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="866" y="223"/>
	<Point x="1278" y="223"/>
	<Point x="1278" y="283"/>
	<Point x="866" y="283"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE HAWFINCH</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1921" y="238"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="238"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="290"/>
	<Point x="1921" y="290"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>47</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="121" y="350"/>
	<Point x="2019" y="350"/>
	<Point x="2019" y="1212"/>
	<Point x="121" y="1212"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>rather pleasing:—The adult male has the head of a cinnamon-brown colour, a line
round the base of the bill, the lores, chin, and throat, black; the nape is smoky
grey; the back and scapulars dull chestnut, somewhat paler on the rump, and
becoming rather yellower on the upper tail-coverts; wings bluish-black, the median
coverts white; the quills with a white patch near the middle of their inner webs,
gradually increasing on the inner feathers, and tipped with blue; the tail-coverts
cinnamon-brown, much elongated; tail feathers black, white at the extremity of
the inner webs: under surface of body pale Dove-brown, fading to white on the
under tail-coverts; beak in summer bluish-grey, darker at the tip; in winter
brownish ﬂesh-coloured; feet ﬂesh-coloured; iris whitish. The female is duller
in colour, with the white markings less pure. The young are without black on
the throat, or grey on the nape; the head is also yellower, and the under surface
of the body whiter; the mantle is mottled, and the breast and ﬂanks are barred
with dark brown.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="114" y="1221"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="1221"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="114" y="1845"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Hawﬁnch is resident with us; but it is probable that at least some of
the young leave our shores at the approach of winter, their places being taken by
immigrants from the north: in the autumn they not infrequently ﬂy into the
nets of the birdcatchers, and are disposed of at very moderate prices. During the
summer months the Hawﬁnch is an exceedingly shy bird, and is far more frequently
heard than seen; its call-note, consisting of a whistle four times repeated, and
drawn out at the ﬁnish, being familiar to most frequenters of its haunts; the
harsh Greenﬁnch-like sound, sometimes mistaken for its call-note, is probably its
cry of deﬁance. The song is a very inferior performance of short duration, some-
what like that of an inferior Greenﬁnch.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="128" y="1850"/>
	<Point x="2019" y="1850"/>
	<Point x="2019" y="2352"/>
	<Point x="128" y="2352"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Hawﬁnch frequents well-wooded localities, such as forest-clearings, small
woods, plantations, shrubberies, heavily timbered parks, where patches of yews or
hawthorn and bramble are left to break the monotony of the landscape, and old
orchards; in such places it builds, varying the site of the nest according to the
haunt which it frequents; thus in a wood or clearing it usually makes its home
in some old hawthorn, tangled with blackberry-vines, or in a holly, or on the
branch of a ﬁr, oak, or beech-tree, some ﬁfteen to thirty feet from the ground;
but in an orchard, an old lichen-covered apple or pear-tree is chosen.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="128" y="2359"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="2359"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="2730"/>
	<Point x="128" y="2730"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest of this bird most nearly resembles that of a Bullﬁnch, being very
shallow, and always formed in a foundation of twigs; one which I found in
course of formation, had the whole of this external structure formed of strongly
spined interlaced twigs of hawthorn, from which all the leaves had been stripped,
and presented a most formidable appearance; sometimes, however, the twigs are
intermixed with coarse roots and dead plants, and ornamented with lichens; the</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
