<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667975">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T06:48:47</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:28</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667975.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="848" y="233"/>
	<Point x="1425" y="233"/>
	<Point x="1425" y="323"/>
	<Point x="848" y="323"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE MEALY REDPOLL</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1987" y="251"/>
	<Point x="2064" y="251"/>
	<Point x="2064" y="330"/>
	<Point x="1987" y="330"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>75</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="186" y="357"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="357"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="620"/>
	<Point x="186" y="620"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>she is also darker above, more prominently streaked below, and wants the rose-
colouring on the rump, the throat, and breast. The young chieﬂy diﬀer from the
female in the lack of crimson on the forehead, and in the more sandy colouring
of the upper parts.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="188" y="628"/>
	<Point x="2084" y="628"/>
	<Point x="2084" y="862"/>
	<Point x="188" y="862"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In conﬁnement, the crimson and rosy colouring entirely disappears after the
ﬁrst moult, excepting in large and well ventilated aviaries, when it is sometimes
partially retained: this statement also applies to the Lesser Redpoll, the Twite,
and the Linnet.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="178" y="877"/>
	<Point x="2086" y="877"/>
	<Point x="2086" y="1306"/>
	<Point x="178" y="1306"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In its habits, this and all the Redpolls are much alike, restless, ﬁdgety little
creatures, Tit-like in their actions, inquisitive, and mischievous; but intelligent,
and, therefore, easy to teach all kinds of meaningless tricks: principally on account
of the last qualiﬁcation they have become favourite cage-birds with that class of
persons which is charmed with what is unnatural. To the true lover of nature
a talking bird may be amusing, because it is the nature of many birds to imitate
sounds; but a performing bird is oﬀensive.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="184" y="1313"/>
	<Point x="2094" y="1313"/>
	<Point x="2094" y="1869"/>
	<Point x="184" y="1869"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Seebohm (Hist. British Birds, Vol. II, pp. 118-119) has some interesting
observations on the habits of this species, both abroad and in this country, which
are worth noting. He says that in winter they are principally ground-feeders,
which we should have expected to be the case from what we know of Linnets and
Goldﬁnches; like which birds they “alight in a ﬂock on a bed of dead thistles,”
and amuse themselves by picking them to pieces. He also records the fact of
their picking seeds from the droppings of horses on the roads; which is instructive,
as showing that they look upon oats and kindred grain as wholesome food; a
fact which aviculture taught me many years ago.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="182" y="1877"/>
	<Point x="2092" y="1877"/>
	<Point x="2092" y="2307"/>
	<Point x="182" y="2307"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest of the Mealy Redpoll is usually placed in the fork of a birch-tree
at no great height from the ground, it has also been found in grass-tussocks; it
is neatly constructed of twigs, bents, strips of bark, and lichens, or moss; the
lining of willow-catkins, vegetable-down, hair, wool, and sometimes feathers. The
eggs number from ﬁve to six, and vary in colour from pale greenish to
pale bluish, with dark brown surface-spots, and paler red-brown underlying
markings.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="180" y="2314"/>
	<Point x="2097" y="2314"/>
	<Point x="2097" y="2611"/>
	<Point x="180" y="2611"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although there is no satisfactory evidence to prove that the Mealy Redpoll
has ever bred in Great Britain, a male in breeding-plumage was observed at
Riddlesworth, in July, 1848, and noticed by Prof. Alfred Newton in the “Zoologist”
(p. 2382); still this bird may possibly have escaped from an out-door aviary after
a few months conﬁnement.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="204" y="2625"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2625"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2746"/>
	<Point x="204" y="2746"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The song of this species, if such it can be called, is merely a prolonged
trill, such as may be imitated either by vibrating the soft palate as you whistle,</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
