<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668217">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T20:15:32</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668217.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="807" y="271"/>
	<Point x="1397" y="271"/>
	<Point x="1397" y="328"/>
	<Point x="807" y="328"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SHORT-TOED LARK</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1923" y="278"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="278"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="338"/>
	<Point x="1923" y="338"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>197</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="141" y="397"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="397"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="580"/>
	<Point x="141" y="580"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>the same situations as the Calandra; they prefer fallow ground, nesting under
shelter of some clod or in any slight depression of the ground. I never could
ﬁnd the nest, except by putting the old bird oﬀ.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="140" y="585"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="585"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="1014"/>
	<Point x="140" y="1014"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Howard Saunders says:—“During the breeding-season the bird frequents
dry and sandy soil, and plains where the herbage is somewhat scanty; while its
tameness is such as often to cause diﬃculty in shooting a specimen for identiﬁcation
without blowing it to pieces, and I have seen a bird cut down with a whip in
the road. The male utters his short and feeble song while perched on some clod
or low wall, or during a brief, undulating, and somewhat jerky ﬂight. In autumn
and winter large ﬂocks are formed.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="147" y="1021"/>
	<Point x="2030" y="1021"/>
	<Point x="2030" y="1264"/>
	<Point x="147" y="1264"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The season of nidiﬁcation, as Seebohm has pointed out, of the Short-toed
Lark varies, commencing at dates decided by the conditions of climate in the
countries where it spends its summer; in the warmer regions it begins as early
as April, whilst in colder countries nesting operations may be delayed until June.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="142" y="1271"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="1271"/>
	<Point x="2023" y="1578"/>
	<Point x="142" y="1578"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest, like that of all its allies, is in a slight depression on the ground,
sometimes barely sheltered by irregularities of the soil, but frequently as with
other Larks, placed amongst grass or partly sheltered by a bush. It is of the
ordinary type, and consists of grass-bents, rootlets, down, and sometimes feathers
with a few hairs as a ﬁnish to the lining.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="145" y="1585"/>
	<Point x="2026" y="1585"/>
	<Point x="2026" y="2200"/>
	<Point x="145" y="2200"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The eggs as well as the nest are very similar to those of our Sky-Lark,
excepting in their inferior size, and (as is the case with that bird) a nest will
sometimes only contain a clutch of three; but I have always considered it probable,
when the normal number of eggs is from four to ﬁve, as with the Short-toed and
Sky-Larks, that the bird has been disturbed in its ﬁrst nest and has had to build
again in a hurry. In colouring the eggs are creamy-whitish freely sprinkled
with pale smoky-brown spots and with greyer shell-spots; these markings are
more or less dense in diﬀerent specimens, sometimes almost concealing the ground-
tint and often with a zone of heavier marking near the larger end; but these
variations are common to all the Larks and might almost be taken for granted.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="152" y="2207"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="2207"/>
	<Point x="2028" y="2573"/>
	<Point x="152" y="2573"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Jerdon (cf Cat. Birds, E. I. Comp., vol. II, p. 473) observes:—“This bird
appears on the table-land of Southern India in October. It associates in vast
ﬂocks, frequenting the bare grass-downs, and is fond of damp spots, as at the
edge of tanks, etc.; it also frequents grain-ﬁelds, and almost always retires to
them for shelter during the heat of the day; from whence it does not in general
issue again till next morning.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="152" y="2579"/>
	<Point x="2021" y="2579"/>
	<Point x="2021" y="2764"/>
	<Point x="152" y="2764"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In his “Birds of India,” vol. II, p. 427, he adds the following facts:—“It
feeds almost entirely on seeds; both runs and hops on the ground, and has a
call-note like that of the real Lark's. Towards the end of March in the south,</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r12" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="254" y="2780"/>
	<Point x="391" y="2780"/>
	<Point x="391" y="2815"/>
	<Point x="254" y="2815"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r18" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1650" y="2778"/>
	<Point x="1740" y="2778"/>
	<Point x="1740" y="2826"/>
	<Point x="1650" y="2826"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>E3</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
