<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667904">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:11:27</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:20</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667904.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="245" y="250"/>
	<Point x="328" y="250"/>
	<Point x="328" y="300"/>
	<Point x="245" y="300"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>40</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="940" y="240"/>
	<Point x="1428" y="240"/>
	<Point x="1428" y="297"/>
	<Point x="940" y="297"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SAND-MARTIN</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="240" y="364"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="364"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="919"/>
	<Point x="240" y="919"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>neatly arranged, each feather lying on its face with the curved under surface
upwards, and the base of the shaft in the centre of the nest: when carefully
removed from the burrows, nests of this character are very pretty; the pinky-white
eggs appearing to lie in a pure white ﬂower-like cup; unhappily a very slight
puﬀ of wind disturbs their symmetry, whilst the removal of the eggs inevitably
displaces the lining, so that one never sees a really perfect Sand-Martin's nest in
any collection. One reason for the slovenliness of many cabinet nests probably
may be, that where nests are abundant, the collector is satisﬁed with those most
readily attainable, and thus fails to secure the best-formed specimens.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="216" y="923"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="923"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="1109"/>
	<Point x="216" y="1109"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The eggs vary in number from four to six, and in form from a long to a
short oval; in colour they are pure white, very slightly glossy, and when freshly
laid show the yolk through the shell, which gives them a rosy appearance.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="1114"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="1114"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="1485"/>
	<Point x="226" y="1485"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The burrows of Sand-Martins, although an irresistible attraction to the birds'-
nester, are often a source of considerable annoyance to railway companies; every
year fresh tunnels are added, as those ﬁrst formed extend too far inwards to please
the birds, one tunnel runs into another, is abandoned, and a new one excavated:
thus the bank of the cutting becomes so much undermined, that frosts and thaws
bring about a land-slip, and a temporary block to traﬃc is occasioned.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="221" y="1488"/>
	<Point x="2126" y="1488"/>
	<Point x="2126" y="1859"/>
	<Point x="221" y="1859"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Of all nests which I have taken, I know of none which so swams with ﬂeas
and ticks as that of the Sand-Martin; the young birds if taken out and examined,
will frequently be found to have large ticks attached to their heads, usually either
on the crown or nape; whilst, in old colonies, the ﬂeas skip about in myriads:
how the poor birds exist under the incessant irritation of these lively vermin is a
puzzle; but perhaps, like the African attacked by chigos, they enjoy the sensation.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="223" y="1866"/>
	<Point x="391" y="1864"/>
	<Point x="907" y="1864"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="1866"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="2107"/>
	<Point x="223" y="2107"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The call-note of this bird is thin and shrill—a sort of sweer: the only attempt
at a song which I have heard is a short low twittering, somewhat vaguely resembling
part of the song of the Reed-Warbler, and usually uttered when two birds meet
in the air and ﬂutter a moment before continuing their onward ﬂight.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="235" y="2114"/>
	<Point x="407" y="2113"/>
	<Point x="489" y="2115"/>
	<Point x="2142" y="2114"/>
	<Point x="2142" y="2750"/>
	<Point x="235" y="2750"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Like the other Swallows, this bird is purely insectivorous; its food principally
consisting of gnats and small ﬂies, which adhere to its viscid saliva, as with wide-
open gape it pursues them in the air: it has been stated to feed its young occa-
sionally with large dragon-ﬂies, but this seems rather improbable, the bodies of
these insects being so long, that (if given entire) they could not be swallowed by
such tiny birds: the only chance is, that the greed of these nestlings which, when
fed, frequently try to swallow one another's heads, might possibly enable them to
tear the body of the dragon-ﬂy in half. The Sand-Martin usually produces two
broods in the year, the ﬁrst nest being rarely full before the beginning of June,
and the second about the middle of July, or even later: the return migration</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
