<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668137">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T15:05:56</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:39</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668137.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1036" y="217"/>
	<Point x="1267" y="217"/>
	<Point x="1267" y="302"/>
	<Point x="1036" y="302"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE JAY</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1982" y="232"/>
	<Point x="2095" y="232"/>
	<Point x="2095" y="294"/>
	<Point x="1982" y="294"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>157</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="217" y="353"/>
	<Point x="2080" y="350"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="478"/>
	<Point x="216" y="481"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>and conspicuous as the bird’s plumage is, it is rarely seen until its harsh note
proclaims its departure to a safer retreat.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="216" y="485"/>
	<Point x="2082" y="481"/>
	<Point x="2083" y="725"/>
	<Point x="216" y="727"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>If not aware of the vicinity of man, however, the Jay is by no means so shy,
his curiosity soon gets the better of his nervousness and he comes into the open
to investigate the cause of every sound; yet he is ever on the alert and the least
sudden movement sends him back instantly to cover.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="216" y="730"/>
	<Point x="2084" y="728"/>
	<Point x="2083" y="1347"/>
	<Point x="214" y="1352"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest of the Jay is believed to be rarely built at a great height from the
ground, of those which I found the highest elevation was about sixteen feet, in
the branches of a sapling too slender to support the weight of a man, so that I
and my companion were compelled to draw it gradually down until I was able to lift
out the nest from its cradle of twigs. My ﬁrst nest was in a plantation of ash-
trees and so near the ground that I was able to lift it down without climbing, it
contained a full clutch of six eggs, and I had no sooner taken it than both
parents, who were close by, made the whole neighbourhood ring with their harsh
screams of rage; I caught a glimpse of one of them, but only for a moment, it
had not suﬃcient courage to come close.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="213" y="1355"/>
	<Point x="2086" y="1349"/>
	<Point x="2080" y="2226"/>
	<Point x="210" y="2225"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest is frequently placed in hawthorn, sloe, hazel, ﬁr, yew, or holly, and
is very compact and strongly built, though externally it has a ragged appearance,
being constructed of interlaced sticks and twigs, which become denser and are
moulded into a neat cup-shape in the centre: the lining consists of rootlets or
grasses and horsehair. The eggs number from ﬁve to seven and, excepting that
their average size is larger, much resemble one of the less typical varieties of the
Blackbird’s egg: in ground colour they are pale green, so densely mottled with
lighter or darker clay-colour that their general tone is either pale olivaceous stone-
colour, or pale clay-colour; at the larger extremity which is usually slightly deeper
in tint, there is very frequently an irregular black line, like a crack: sometimes
the darker area forms a scarcely perceptible zone, the extremity itself being quite
pale. The time of nidiﬁcation is from the latter end of April to about the middle
of May, most nests being found in the second month; but it has been known for
the Jay to be still later, perhaps owing to a ﬁrst nest having been plundered.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="210" y="2227"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="2229"/>
	<Point x="2082" y="2727"/>
	<Point x="210" y="2724"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The food of this bird consists in summer of worms, spiders, insects, eggs,
young birds, and fruit; but later in the year, chieﬂy of berries, acorns, beech-
mast and nuts. In captivity its food is still more varied, Mr. J. H. Gurney,
(Zoologist 1892, p. 429), gives the following as the diet supplied to two tame Jays—
“The ﬁrst one would eat worms, grapes and acorns, with equal avidity; but its
beak could not pierce the acorn’s husk until it had been partly pared oﬀ, then
holding it with its foot the bird would rapidly pull it to pieces with its strong
beak. In the same way, if a dead sparrow is given to a Jay, it will stand on one</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1737" y="2738"/>
	<Point x="1737" y="2783"/>
	<Point x="1817" y="2783"/>
	<Point x="1817" y="2738"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>S2</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="317" y="2741"/>
	<Point x="317" y="2782"/>
	<Point x="450" y="2782"/>
	<Point x="450" y="2741"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
