<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667920">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:13:09</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:22</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667920.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="259" y="273"/>
	<Point x="333" y="273"/>
	<Point x="333" y="333"/>
	<Point x="259" y="333"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>48</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="990" y="261"/>
	<Point x="1397" y="261"/>
	<Point x="1397" y="323"/>
	<Point x="990" y="323"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE HAWFINCH</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="242" y="392"/>
	<Point x="2135" y="392"/>
	<Point x="2135" y="885"/>
	<Point x="242" y="885"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>nest itself is built of dead grasses and bents, and the lining consists of rootlets
and hair: altogether it is so large that the Wood-Pigeon has been known to add
a few twigs to it, and thus adapt it to its own purposes.* The eggs number
from four to six, though ﬁve is the usual complement; they are pale bluish or
buﬃsh-green in colour, and vary in pattern between that of the Common-and
Reed-Buntings, the surface spots, blotches, and streaks being deep pitch-brown,
with underlying spots of lilacine-grey: in size and form they correspond pretty
closely with eggs of the Common Bunting.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="250" y="890"/>
	<Point x="2135" y="890"/>
	<Point x="2135" y="1135"/>
	<Point x="250" y="1135"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The ﬂight of the Hawﬁnch is rapid and powerful, somewhat undulating when
the bird is passing from tree to tree, but more direct when long distances are
covered. On the wing it often utters a peculiar clicking sound, a kind of tic,
which may also sometimes be heard when the bird is caged.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="247" y="1142"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="1142"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="1450"/>
	<Point x="247" y="1450"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The food consists largely of seeds, those of the hornbean being much relished;
but when feeding its young it devours insects, especially caterpillars, and probably
buds; later in the year peas, cherry-kernels, beech-mast, yew-berries, and haws
are eaten. In conﬁnement sunﬂower-seeds, hemp, oats, beech-nuts, canary, and
millet may be given.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="247" y="1454"/>
	<Point x="2126" y="1454"/>
	<Point x="2126" y="2064"/>
	<Point x="247" y="2064"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Personally I have had but little experience of the Hawﬁnch as a cage-bird.
On September 14th, 1893, a birdcatcher brought me a specimen which had ﬂown
into his nets: he was evidently afraid to handle it, and cautioned me against
attempting to touch it without gloves, saying that its bite was frightful and drew
blood; however I soon had the bird in my hand and caged it; but, although I
placed the cage on a high shelf, the Hawﬁnch never became tame, but so wore
the feathers of its wings and tail by its eﬀorts to escape, that when after a few
weeks of captivity it died, the skin was not worth preserving. I am, therefore,
convinced that the Hawﬁnch should either be turned into a large aviary, or be
hand-reared.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="242" y="2078"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="2078"/>
	<Point x="2138" y="2565"/>
	<Point x="242" y="2565"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Speaking of a pair taken from the nest and brought to him in 1880, the late Lord
Lilford says:—“My two caged Hawﬁnches * * readily devoured meal-worms and
house-ﬂies, but I imagine that this is an unnatural and acquired taste.” In this
I think his Lordship was in error, for there can be nothing unnatural in a bird
largely reared upon partly digested caterpillars, subsequently eating mealworms.
Ripe apples would probably be a welcome addition to its prison-diet; for, according
to Mr. Horatio Fillmer, of Brighton, the Black-tailed Hawﬁnch is especially
fond of fruit.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="347" y="2578"/>
	<Point x="2128" y="2578"/>
	<Point x="2128" y="2645"/>
	<Point x="347" y="2645"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As a pet the Hawﬁnch has but little to recommend it; it is not a pretty</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="252" y="2673"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="2673"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="2766"/>
	<Point x="252" y="2766"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* When I wrote my “Handbook of British Oology” I had not found one ﬁnished nest of the Hawﬁnch;
one or two seen subsequently in Hertfordshire had already been deserted.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
