<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668031">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T20:24:36</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:32</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668031.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="844" y="205"/>
	<Point x="1276" y="205"/>
	<Point x="1276" y="280"/>
	<Point x="844" y="280"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE BRAMBLING</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="112" y="334"/>
	<Point x="1988" y="334"/>
	<Point x="1988" y="584"/>
	<Point x="112" y="584"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>tail-feathers have fairly broad yellow margins; the feathers of the sides of the
neck have ashy edges; the sides and ﬂanks are washed with orange-tawny, the
black spots on the ﬂanks are less prominent, and the beak becomes bright ochre-
yellow, with brown tip.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="112" y="595"/>
	<Point x="1989" y="595"/>
	<Point x="1989" y="835"/>
	<Point x="112" y="835"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The female somewhat resembles the male in winter plumage but is altogether
duller, the black of the upper parts being replaced by brown, and the bars on the
wings are much less prominent. The young at ﬁrst are very like the female,
but the males quickly develop their characteristic colouring.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="114" y="843"/>
	<Point x="1989" y="843"/>
	<Point x="1989" y="959"/>
	<Point x="114" y="959"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The breeding plumage of the male is acquired without a moult, and it is said
that the change is eﬀected by shedding the tips of the feathers.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="116" y="966"/>
	<Point x="1992" y="966"/>
	<Point x="1992" y="1523"/>
	<Point x="116" y="1523"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although somewhat less active than the Chaﬃnch, this species is quite as
quarrelsome in the breeding season (at any rate in conﬁnement); in winter, how‑
ever, the ﬂocks which travel about through woods and over ﬁelds in search of
food agree perfectly with one another and with Chaﬃnches. Speaking of them as
observed near Sheﬃeld, Seebohm observes:—“They are remarkable noisy birds, and
sit upon the tree-tops twittering to each other until dusk; they sometimes ﬂy up
into the air in a compact mass, and after wheeling round several times again alight.
They roost in the yew and holly trees, and a fair proportion of them seek quarters
in the ivy.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="116" y="1527"/>
	<Point x="1992" y="1527"/>
	<Point x="1992" y="2337"/>
	<Point x="116" y="2337"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The site chosen by the Brambling for its nest is usually at a height of from
ﬁfteen to twenty feet from the ground in a birch or ﬁr-tree, at the junction of a
branch with the trunk; the nest has, however, been found in juniper bushes. In
his “Catalogue of Birds of the Dyke Road Museum, at Brighton,” p. 126, the late
Mr. E. T. Booth says:—“In the summer of 1866, while ﬁshing on the river Lyon,
in Perthshire, I had occasion to climb a beech-tree to release the line which had
become entangled in the branches, and while so engaged a female Brambling was
disturbed from her nest, containing three eggs, which was placed close to the stem
of the tree. As I was anxious to procure the young I left her, and on visiting
the spot in about a fortnight the nest was empty, and, judging by its appearance,
I should be of opinion that the young birds had been dragged out by a cat. This
is the only instance I have ever known of the Brambling attempting to rear its
young in Great Britain.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="117" y="2346"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="2346"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="2523"/>
	<Point x="117" y="2523"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the “Field” for July 23rd, 1864, p. 52, the Rev. J. C. Atkinson recorded
the fact of a nest with ﬁve or six eggs having been taken at Baldersby Park, near
Thirsk, Yorks., by the Hon. Guy Dawnay.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="118" y="2535"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="2535"/>
	<Point x="1991" y="2714"/>
	<Point x="118" y="2714"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest is larger and more coarsely made than that of the Chaﬃnch, being
formed of white and buﬀ birch-bark, moss, lichens, and spiders’ web, and lined
with ﬁne grass and feathers. The eggs, ﬁve to seven, usually six, in number, are</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1896" y="208"/>
	<Point x="2025" y="208"/>
	<Point x="2025" y="294"/>
	<Point x="1896" y="294"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>103</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
