<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667864">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-11T06:37:25</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:16</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667864.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="804" y="300"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="300"/>
	<Point x="1446" y="343"/>
	<Point x="804" y="343"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SPOTTED FLYCATCHER</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="203" y="424"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="424"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="539"/>
	<Point x="203" y="539"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Persia, Turkestan, and Siberia as far as Irkutsk. In winter it visits India, Arabia,
and Africa to the Cape of Good Hope.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="202" y="549"/>
	<Point x="2053" y="549"/>
	<Point x="2053" y="787"/>
	<Point x="202" y="787"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In Great Britain the Spotted Flycatcher breeds in suitable localities in every
county, but in England and Wales it is far more abundant, and more generally
distributed than in Scotland and Ireland: its distribution in the latter island is
certainly local, and it is probable that some counties are unsuited to its requirements.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="203" y="799"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="799"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="1344"/>
	<Point x="203" y="1344"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The colouring of this bird is decidedly sombre, its upper surface being brown,
slightly paler and with dark shaft-streaks on the crown; the wings and tail darker
brown, with paler margins to the wing-coverts and secondaries: its under surface
is greyish-white; the breast and ﬂanks slightly buﬀ-brownish, and streaked with
brown, as also is the throat; bill dark brown; feet black; iris dark hazel. The
female greatly resembles the male, but is somewhat browner and is more heavily
streaked on the underparts. The young have buﬀ centres to the feathers of the
upper surface, whilst the wing-coverts, secondaries, and tail-coverts are tipped with
this colour.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="202" y="1362"/>
	<Point x="2054" y="1362"/>
	<Point x="2054" y="2656"/>
	<Point x="202" y="2656"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Spotted Flycatcher haunts the outskirts of woods, high hedges on the
borders of parks and pleasure grounds, plantations of hazel, orchards, and gardens,
and in such places it breeds, usually placing its nest either in a slight depression
in the branch of a tree, frequently near the trunk, or on the branch of a fruit-tree
trained against a wall; it has, however, been known to build in crevices of the
bark of old trees, in trellis-work overgrown with creepers, and I have taken the
nest from the hollow top of a tree stump, from a tall hawthorn hedge, and one in
my collection was taken from a narrow hole in a wall.* The form of the nest
varies in accordance with its surroundings; if placed upon a branch or in the top
of a hedge it is circular, if on a fruit-branch trained against a wall, semicircular,
and the nest which I obtained from a hole in a wall was of the exact shape of a small
slipper; the materials of the nest also vary somewhat, but they generally consist
of twigs and roots, or ﬁne grasses, mixed with a quantity of green moss interwoven
with spiders’ webs, and lined with ﬁne grass, hair, and sometimes two or three
feathers. The eggs vary in number from three to six, ﬁve being the most usual
number, the ground colour being frequently pale pea-green, but sometimes bluish-
white, blotched, zoned, mottled or spotted with various depths of ferruginous red-
brown; when the mottling is very dense the egg, excepting in its inferior size
and narrower shape, somewhat reminds one of that of the Robin, and when the
markings are chieﬂy represented by a zone near the larger end, it vaguely suggests
that of the Greenﬁnch.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="212" y="2713"/>
	<Point x="2049" y="2713"/>
	<Point x="2049" y="2780"/>
	<Point x="212" y="2780"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* It is said also to have been found among roots overhanging water, and in metal gutters on roofs of
houses.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="209" y="309"/>
	<Point x="258" y="309"/>
	<Point x="258" y="341"/>
	<Point x="209" y="341"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>22</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
