<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668006">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T20:21:58</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:30</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668006.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="171" y="237"/>
	<Point x="249" y="237"/>
	<Point x="249" y="312"/>
	<Point x="171" y="312"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>90</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="826" y="207"/>
	<Point x="1380" y="207"/>
	<Point x="1380" y="307"/>
	<Point x="826" y="307"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE HOUSE‐SPARROW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="175" y="337"/>
	<Point x="2036" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2036" y="598"/>
	<Point x="174" y="604"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Madeira. In Africa it occurs from Morocco to the Albert Nyanza. It has been
introduced into Australia, New Zealand, and the United States, where it has
increased to such an extent as to be an unbearable nuisance. (Vide Sharpe and
Saunders).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="174" y="607"/>
	<Point x="2036" y="603"/>
	<Point x="2035" y="846"/>
	<Point x="175" y="850"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Throughout Great Britain and Ireland, wherever man has made his home,
the Sparrow has quickly followed his example, even isolated houses usually
providing a pretext for the presence of this bird, sometimes to the extent of scores
of individuals.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="176" y="853"/>
	<Point x="2036" y="851"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="1963"/>
	<Point x="170" y="1970"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The adult male Sparrow in breeding plumage has the crown, nape, and lower
back slate-grey, slightly washed with olivaceous, but the sides of the nape bright
chocolate-reddish in continuation of a broad streak from the ear-coverts; upper
back blackish, each feather broadly bordered with dull chestnut; lesser wing-coverts
bright chocolate-reddish; median coverts black, broadly tipped with white so as
to form a prominent bar across the wing; greater coverts blackish, broadly bordered
with dull chestnut; primaries blackish-grey, all excepting the ﬁrst with pale
chestnut edging to the wider part of the outer web, but the inner primaries with
this edge continuous; secondaries blackish, with chestnut borders, paler and greyer
on the inner webs; tail blackish-brown, the feathers edged with whity-brown; a
narrow white line over the eye; lores black; cheeks, and sides of neck white;
throat and chest black, sometimes suﬀused with chocolate; remainder of under
parts white, ashy at the sides, and brownish on the ﬂanks; beak leaden-black;
feet brown; iris brown. After the autumn moult the male has whitish-ash fringes
to the feathers of the head and throat, which appear to be very delicate in texture,
and break away in the spring;* the under parts are also more uniformly ashy,
the upper parts duller, the wing band yellowish, and the beak becomes yellowish-
brown.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="170" y="1979"/>
	<Point x="2040" y="1972"/>
	<Point x="2044" y="2285"/>
	<Point x="968" y="2287"/>
	<Point x="170" y="2287"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The female is duller and browner than the male; the broad borders to the
feathers of the mantle and back being tawny rather than chestnut; the superciliary
line and wing bar less pure and conspicuous; the under parts browner, with no
black on throat and chest. Young birds chieﬂy diﬀer from the female in their
paler colouring; the beak is dull yellow.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="170" y="2291"/>
	<Point x="2046" y="2291"/>
	<Point x="2047" y="2606"/>
	<Point x="169" y="2599"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In towns the House-Sparrow is a useful bird, inasmuch as it feeds largely on
oats and other grain which it picks from horse-manure, and which otherwise would
render the latter less suitable for garden purposes; it also acts as a scavenger,
eating scraps of all kinds which have been thrown into the gutters, and which if
not removed in warm weather would soon become oﬀensive. In very dry seasons,</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="184" y="2633"/>
	<Point x="2030" y="2638"/>
	<Point x="2030" y="2726"/>
	<Point x="183" y="2724"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* This I do not give on the authority of previous writers, although they mention the fact, but on the
clear evidence of a good skin (in my possession) of a bird which died in the middle of its change of plumage.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
