<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667942">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-11T06:45:22</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:25</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667942.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="256" y="281"/>
	<Point x="337" y="281"/>
	<Point x="337" y="352"/>
	<Point x="256" y="352"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>58</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="995" y="274"/>
	<Point x="1404" y="274"/>
	<Point x="1404" y="339"/>
	<Point x="995" y="339"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE BULLFINCH</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="250" y="394"/>
	<Point x="2141" y="394"/>
	<Point x="2141" y="527"/>
	<Point x="250" y="527"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>cause of the melanism, which may have been due to keeping the birds in a
moist warm atmosphere.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="251" y="530"/>
	<Point x="2151" y="530"/>
	<Point x="2151" y="964"/>
	<Point x="251" y="964"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>During the summer months the Bullﬁnch chieﬂy haunts the outskirts of woods,
plantations, dense shrubberies, private pleasure grounds, where clumps of conifers
with tangled undergrowth of brambles have been left, to vary the landscape or to
form cover for game, or clearings covered with two or three year’s growth; less
frequently lanes skirted by tall hedges; but never far from woods. In such places
it builds its shallow nest, and once I found one in a loose wayside hazel-hedge,
about three feet high and quite at the top, barely concealed by a leaf.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="241" y="968"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="968"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="2024"/>
	<Point x="241" y="2024"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The favourite site for the nest is on the upper surface of a horizontal branch
of a spruce-ﬁr, or yew; but I have also met with it in dwarf hawthorns tangled
with blackberry vines, and in the side of a hawthorn, half buried by elm-foliage,
on the edge of a wood: sometimes a small box-tree is selected, or very rarely a
slight gap in a tall hedge. The outer framework of the nest consists of a tangled
platform of slender twigs or roots, surrounding a neat, and sometimes stoutly
built, but usually somewhat frail looking cup of plaited rootlets and bents, with
a lining of root-ﬁbre and black horse-hairs. According to Seebohm “in some
nests a little wool or a feather or two are found,” but I never found either,
though occasionally a dead leaf drifts into the cup and is left there. The eggs
number from four to six, but rarely exceed ﬁve; in colour they are pale blue,
sometimes almost white; spotted with blackish-brown, mixed with spots or blotches
of purplish, red-brown, and now and then lavender; most eggs are chieﬂy spotted
at or near the larger end; sometimes there are one or two Bunting markings
among the spots; rarely the zone of markings occurs near the smaller end of the
egg; and lastly, in the very aberrant, almost white variety, the whole of the
spots are chocolate-brown diﬀused at the edges.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="245" y="2029"/>
	<Point x="2145" y="2029"/>
	<Point x="2145" y="2216"/>
	<Point x="245" y="2216"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>There is no doubt that, when feeding its young, the Bullﬁnch eats aphides,
small green caterpillars, seeds, and leaves of weeds; so that, in a measure, it
atones for the mischief which it does to the fruit-grower in autumn and spring.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="244" y="2220"/>
	<Point x="2141" y="2220"/>
	<Point x="2141" y="2786"/>
	<Point x="244" y="2786"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is said that the Bullﬁnch frequently rears two broods in the season; its
ﬁrst eggs being laid towards the end of April; the young would, therefore, be
hatched early in May, and perhaps be able to look after themselves by the end
of that month; the second nest, if built in the last week of May, would again
have eggs by the end of the ﬁrst week in June. My own experience is that, in
Kent, nidiﬁcation is later; the ﬁrst nest having eggs in the early part of May,
and the second early in July, so that the old birds must be close upon, or in
their moult by the time that the young leave the nest. Is it certain that these
birds would be reared? I am inclined to doubt it. In 1890 a pair of Bullﬁnches</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
