<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668177">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-09T23:10:43</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:42</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668177.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="883" y="214"/>
	<Point x="1382" y="214"/>
	<Point x="1382" y="292"/>
	<Point x="883" y="292"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE HOODED CROW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1971" y="237"/>
	<Point x="2052" y="237"/>
	<Point x="2052" y="291"/>
	<Point x="1971" y="291"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>177</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="196" y="335"/>
	<Point x="2066" y="347"/>
	<Point x="2068" y="1032"/>
	<Point x="186" y="1038"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>important; as showing how little the agency of man can aﬀect the extinction of
species, so far as it is directed merely against birds, their nests and eggs:—
“Finally, I would add one further remark, as regards the position of these Crows
in the economy of nature. Everywhere the protection of birds creates the greatest
interest, and man is always put in the foreground as the greatest enemy of the
feathered creation. Now, although the destruction of song-birds and other small
species, as it appears to be carried on in Italy, ought to be resisted by all possible
means; nevertheless all that is oﬀered for sale, in the way of eggs and small
birds, in Italy during one complete migration period, would scarcely equal the
quantity of eggs and nestlings destroyed by the Hooded Crows during one single
summer day.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="187" y="1040"/>
	<Point x="2067" y="1037"/>
	<Point x="2076" y="2017"/>
	<Point x="197" y="2033"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“It is perhaps true that the number of individuals of Hooded Crows becomes
nowhere apparent in such prepondering quantity as in Heligoland, in consequence
of which their destructive inﬂuence is under-estimated; but if one had the oppor‐
tunity of seeing the hosts of them which travel past during two months of
autumn, in uninterrupted sequence, and return in the spring, as is the case here,
where no tree, wood, or hill, impedes the view; and if one at the same time
remembers that all these fellows, impudent as they are cunning, do nothing else
during the long summer days, from early dawn to sunset, but plunder the nests
of other birds, from the Lark to the Eagle (Dresser), one would indeed wonder
that there are still any birds, other than Hooded Crows, left in the world. By
all means let us nurture and protect our little bird-friends in every possible
manner, more especially by abstaining from destroying any small shrubbery or
bush, the sole use of which may, perhaps, be that it aﬀords some small songster
a hidden nook for its nest; above everything, however, let us aim at compassing
the destruction of Hooded Crows unsparingly, year in year out, by all the means
placed at our command.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="200" y="2042"/>
	<Point x="197" y="2035"/>
	<Point x="2078" y="2021"/>
	<Point x="2078" y="2328"/>
	<Point x="1372" y="2334"/>
	<Point x="197" y="2341"/>
	<Point x="197" y="2337"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nidiﬁcation of this species is similar to that of the Carrion-Crow; in
Ireland it commences about the middle of March, but in Scotland later; the nest
does not diﬀer from that of C. corone, and is similarly situated, although it has
been found built on the roofs of huts, according to Gray. The eggs are precisely
like those of the Carrion-Crow in all their varieties.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="198" y="2343"/>
	<Point x="2078" y="2333"/>
	<Point x="2078" y="2468"/>
	<Point x="199" y="2467"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The cries of this species and of C. corone are indistinguishable, and the food
is the same; but the Hooded Crow is bolder and even more destructive.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="199" y="2471"/>
	<Point x="2076" y="2471"/>
	<Point x="2074" y="2720"/>
	<Point x="202" y="2722"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Dixon is the only Ornithologist who seems to have a good word to say for
this Crow; he says:—“I must confess that, in spite of the dark tales of plunder
and his questionable mode of getting a livelihood, the Hooded Crow is a favourite
bird of mine, and his habits and regular movements never fail to interest me.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="313" y="2740"/>
	<Point x="437" y="2740"/>
	<Point x="437" y="2772"/>
	<Point x="313" y="2772"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1735" y="2737"/>
	<Point x="1792" y="2737"/>
	<Point x="1792" y="2774"/>
	<Point x="1735" y="2774"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Z2</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
