<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668168">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T07:09:24</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:41</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668168.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="271" y="179"/>
	<Point x="381" y="179"/>
	<Point x="381" y="234"/>
	<Point x="271" y="234"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>172</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="941" y="162"/>
	<Point x="1460" y="162"/>
	<Point x="1460" y="244"/>
	<Point x="941" y="244"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE CARRION-CROW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="273" y="297"/>
	<Point x="2140" y="296"/>
	<Point x="2140" y="666"/>
	<Point x="270" y="670"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In Great Britain this species is justly disliked and persecuted, both by
shepherds and game-keepers; yet it is still by no means rare in the well-timbered
portions of England and Wales, becoming, however, decidedly commoner in the
northern counties, whilst in Scotland it is abundant; in the islands oﬀ the
Scotch coast it again becomes scarce and it is doubtful whether it really occurs
in the Orkneys or Shetlands. In Ireland it is a very scarce bird.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="270" y="673"/>
	<Point x="2142" y="669"/>
	<Point x="2139" y="1043"/>
	<Point x="270" y="1042"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The male Carrion-Crow is glossy black; purplish above, and with green
tints on the head and neck; the wings similarly tinted; bill and feet black;
iris brown. The female is perhaps slightly less glossy than the male, but does
not otherwise diﬀer in plumage; her bill appears to be longer and more slender
than that of the male, which is unusual in the Crows. Young birds are without
gloss and the inside of their mouths is pale ﬂesh-coloured.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="265" y="1046"/>
	<Point x="2142" y="1045"/>
	<Point x="2145" y="1733"/>
	<Point x="263" y="1730"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As opposed to the absurd notion that because this species is proved to
hybridize freely with the Hooded Crow and produce fertile oﬀspring, it cannot be
a distinct species, Herr Gätke shrewdly observes:—“The very circumstance,
however, that despite pairing having taken place for several thousands of years,
the two colours of the respective species have remained pure and distinct, forms
the most striking proof of the speciﬁc independence of the two; for, if they had
not existed originally as two ﬁxed primary forms, to which the mongrel oﬀspring
reverted, though this may have occurred only after several generations, we should
at present know neither the one species nor the other in its pure simple
colouration, but should meet only with unlimited gradational stages of mixtures
of grey and black forms.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="264" y="1732"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="1736"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="2230"/>
	<Point x="264" y="2233"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>This argument, however, is not unassailable, unless it be claimed that the
three Pheasants—P. colchicus, P. torquatus, and P. versicolor, which also interbreed
freely and produce endless intergrades are, therefore, not distinct species. It must
also be borne in mind that in some cases acknowledged sports of the same
species when crossed do not produce intergrades, but from one clutch of eggs
reproduce examples of each variety, as has been proved in the case of the
Barbary Turtle-Dove, the Gouldian Finch, and the supposed fertile hybrid known
as the Bengalee.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="263" y="2236"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="2233"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="2680"/>
	<Point x="263" y="2677"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In many respects the Carrion-Crow resembles the Raven, inhabiting similar
haunts, whether among the rocky uplands, or in woods and game-coverts. In its
predatory habits it is almost, if not quite as much dreaded, both by shepherd
and game-keeper. Ever seeking for food from dawn till dark, the mischief done
by a pair of this species in a single season must be enormous. That this bird
has some courage seems probable from the fact that it will sometimes dispute
with a Gull or even a small Hawk, but it appears soon to weary of resisting a</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
