<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667992">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T12:20:32</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:29</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667992.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="235" y="180"/>
	<Point x="330" y="180"/>
	<Point x="330" y="253"/>
	<Point x="235" y="253"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>84</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1026" y="171"/>
	<Point x="1355" y="171"/>
	<Point x="1355" y="253"/>
	<Point x="1026" y="253"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE TWITE</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="217" y="280"/>
	<Point x="2158" y="280"/>
	<Point x="2158" y="1419"/>
	<Point x="217" y="1419"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>same time, I gave her two of the Twites’ eggs, making up the number for each
with infertile eggs; both birds hatched on the same day; the two in the Redpoll’s
nest perished at once, though she is a good feeder, and has reared two broods of
her own this season; the Twite successfully reared hers, and they left the nest
on July 19th, and are now very ﬁne birds, but quite normally coloured; this I
expected, as I have reared a large number during the past few years from both
white, pied, and cinnamon Lesser Redpolls, and have inbred them, but have never
had one vary in the least from the normal colour.* Young Twites are not nearly
so precocious as Redpolls; they were a long time before they attempted to peck
for themselves, and even now (August) clamour to the old ones for food, whereas
I have seen young Redpolls a week after leaving the nest shell hard Canary-seed.
My birds have no soft food given them, but as much of the ﬂowering top of the
dwarf-grass, dandelion, and hard-head tops, thistle, plantain, etc., as they wish, and
as many aphides oﬀ rose, apple, or plum-trees as I can at the time obtain; infested
branches being put in the aviary for the birds to peck them oﬀ. The latter, I
consider, are very essential for the successful rearing of Finches in conﬁnement,
especially for the ﬁrst few days after they are hatched.”†</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="341" y="2558"/>
	<Point x="1967" y="2558"/>
	<Point x="1967" y="2698"/>
	<Point x="341" y="2698"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* Nevertheless continuous inbreeding is believed to be the principal cause of albinism.—A.G.B.
† If soft food is given, I do not ﬁnd aphides to be essential.—A G.B.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r5">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1075" y="1932"/>
	<Point x="1075" y="1982"/>
	<Point x="1303" y="1982"/>
	<Point x="1303" y="1932"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
