<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668162">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T01:38:47</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:41</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668162.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1026" y="162"/>
	<Point x="1360" y="162"/>
	<Point x="1360" y="223"/>
	<Point x="1026" y="223"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE RAVEN</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="257" y="294"/>
	<Point x="2120" y="294"/>
	<Point x="2120" y="415"/>
	<Point x="257" y="415"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>from his pouch, rearrange the feathers, and hop oﬀ with the air of having done
a very clever thing.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="251" y="420"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="420"/>
	<Point x="2123" y="973"/>
	<Point x="251" y="973"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As regards the possibility of this species breeding in conﬁnement, I may
quote the following note given to me by Mr. J. E. Harting for my “Handbook
of British Oology” :—“In March, 1864, a pair of tame Ravens which had the run
of a garden belonging to Mr. Winterbottom, of Cheltenham, built a nest in a
box in a shed about six feet from the ground. The nest was built of sticks, old
fern-leaves, and the stalks of dead wall-ﬂowers, and was lined with dead leaves
and tufts of grass. On March 4th two eggs were found in the nest, and the
following day a third was laid; but the hen bird did not sit well, perhaps
because too much disturbed by visitors, and the eggs were not hatched.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="252" y="979"/>
	<Point x="2124" y="979"/>
	<Point x="2124" y="1162"/>
	<Point x="252" y="1162"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Lord Lilford’s last pair of Ravens, which, however, had considerable liberty,
reared four young ones, all of which were living in 1894. In 1908 Mr. St.
Quintin's Ravens hatched out ﬁve strong young ones.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="250" y="1169"/>
	<Point x="2130" y="1169"/>
	<Point x="2130" y="2672"/>
	<Point x="250" y="2672"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Mr. J. H. Comyns, of Lyvenden, S. Devon, forwarded to me a full account of
a Raven and Buzzard taken by him in 1896 from nests in trees:—“The Raven
was perfectly, I may say aggressively, tame within a week, but the Buzzard
remained obdurate for fully three times as long, his timidity and suspicion being
truly exasperating.” “As soon as my bird was full-grown, I tried the
experiment of turning him in with ‘Grip’ the Raven (who is conﬁned in a
disused stable on account of his depredations in the neighbours’ gardens). As I
anticipated, ‘Grip’ instantly dashed at the intruder with murderous intent, but
what followed was a surprise to me. The Buzzard, after ﬂying two or three
times round the stable, hotly pursued by ‘Grip,’ suddenly alighted on the ﬂoor
and confronted him with every feather bristling. The valour of the sable bird of
Odin was evidently tempered with a wholesome caution; he stopped too, with
ruﬄed head held low down and open beak, panting like a hound, whereupon the
Buzzard to his astonishment and consternation sprang at him. He instantly beat
a headlong retreat, and the victor, after pursuing him for a short time from
perch to perch, rested on his laurels. For a fortnight after this, the Buzzard
was master of the situation, and the Raven got nothing in the shape of meat to
eat unless I was there to give it to him. The Buzzard would stoop at him and
snatch his food out of his very beak, as he unearthed it from his various hiding-
places. ‘Grip’ now changed his tactics, and took to sneaking up behind and
furtively tweaking the Buzzard’s wings or tail, and strange to say, a persistent
course of these harrassing attacks has now utterly destroyed the Buzzard’s spirit,
evidently too superﬁcial to stand at all a severe test, and reduced him from a
really noble-looking bird to a woe-begone wretch, denuded of both tail-feathers</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="267" y="175"/>
	<Point x="380" y="175"/>
	<Point x="380" y="255"/>
	<Point x="267" y="255"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>170</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
