<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668114">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T07:03:35</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:37</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668114.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="773" y="192"/>
	<Point x="1580" y="192"/>
	<Point x="1580" y="269"/>
	<Point x="773" y="269"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE ROSE‐COLOURED STARLING</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="257" y="334"/>
	<Point x="2117" y="334"/>
	<Point x="2117" y="452"/>
	<Point x="257" y="452"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>bearable; but, to see Starlings to perfection, they should be kept in a good-sized
aviary.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="255" y="463"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="463"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="1515"/>
	<Point x="255" y="1515"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>I have frequently seen Pastor roseus oﬀered for sale, but was not suﬃciently
struck with the bird to give the price required for it. Herr Wiener, however,
observes (Cassell’s Cage-birds, p. 424):—“I doubted the accounts I had read of
Starlings waging a war of extermination against locusts and grasshoppers; till
seeing one day a Rose-coloured Pastor oﬀered for sale, I remembered that I had
a hot-pit over-run with crickets, and resolved to try an experiment. The Pastor
was placed in an aviary, and I proceeded to catch crickets by placing balls of
crumpled brown paper into the warmest corners of the pit. Hundreds of lively
crickets could be shaken out of the papers in the morning, and I could thus
produce at pleasure something like a swarm of grasshoppers. A well-bred terrier
will face any number of his natural enemies—rats; but his zeal is nothing com‐
pared to the Pastor’s powers of methodical destruction of grasshoppers and crickets.
The crickets covered the ground on which the bird stood: they ran up his legs
and over his body, and coolly would he peck away, devouring one after the other,
until none were left. Where he put all the insects seemed incomprehensible;
but the immense services which such insectivorous birds, with endless appetites,
can render to the agriculturist are palpable.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="254" y="1524"/>
	<Point x="2113" y="1524"/>
	<Point x="2113" y="1945"/>
	<Point x="254" y="1945"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In conﬁnement this species should be fed like the Common Starling upon
the usual soft food, with the addition of such fruit as happens to be in season,
and any insects which can be obtained. Doubtless, like Sturnus vulgaris, it would
be all the better if allowed to have access to a saucer of seed: the fact that the
bird is a perfect scourge in the Indian ﬁelds of white millet being a suﬃcient
answer to those aviculturists who assert that seed is an unnatural food for insect‐
ivorous birds.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="251" y="210"/>
	<Point x="358" y="210"/>
	<Point x="358" y="271"/>
	<Point x="251" y="271"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>146</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r6">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1060" y="2300"/>
	<Point x="1300" y="2300"/>
	<Point x="1300" y="2336"/>
	<Point x="1060" y="2336"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
