<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668170">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-09T20:09:39</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:41</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668170.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="278" y="201"/>
	<Point x="389" y="201"/>
	<Point x="389" y="275"/>
	<Point x="278" y="275"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>174</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="971" y="167"/>
	<Point x="1467" y="167"/>
	<Point x="1467" y="257"/>
	<Point x="971" y="257"/>
	<Point x="964" y="213"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE CARRION-CROW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="266" y="313"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2145" y="502"/>
	<Point x="265" y="502"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>of all kinds are devoured greedily, as well as insects, their larvæ, and grain. In
the winter he is more limited and has to content himself with grain, berries, and
such weakly half-starved birds or beasts as he can manage to kill.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="267" y="505"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="504"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="1441"/>
	<Point x="266" y="1440"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Mr. O. V. Aplin (“Zoologist,” 1883, p. 409) published the following note on
the food of this species:—“An old disused bridle-gate standing near one corner
of Clattercutt Reservoir has this season served as a feeding spot for a pair of
Carrion-Crows, which reared their young in a tall elm on one side of the pool.
One evening in June, after the grass was cut, I found strewn around it the
remains of several toads and frogs, and of one partly ﬂedged nestling ﬁnch, also
a number of broken shells of the eggs of the Wild Duck and Partridge. The
state the gate was in showed that it was a much frequented perch, and a tell-tale
wing-feather would have named the robber even if he had not hurriedly left an
adjacent tree at my approach, and with loud croaks expressed his displeasure at
my intrusion on his banqueting hall. I have always tried to defend this ﬁne
bird, and was sorry to ﬁnd such ample proof of its destructive habits. Only a
few days ago (October 1883) I counted thirty-two Crows in a stubble-ﬁeld close
to this village, and considering their abundance in this district, it is only a
wonder that any game or wildfowl can rear their young at all.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="267" y="1442"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="1443"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="1626"/>
	<Point x="268" y="1628"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although inclined to a solitary life during the breeding-season* the Carrion-
Crow is seen in larger or smaller crowds during the autumn and winter: con‐
siderable numbers arrive on our eastern coasts in autumn.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="268" y="1630"/>
	<Point x="2152" y="1628"/>
	<Point x="2152" y="2141"/>
	<Point x="267" y="2139"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Seebohm’s statement that this bird “makes almost as engaging a pet as the
Raven” hardly accords with Lord Lilford’s opinion of the Carrion-Crow. The
following is Mr. Bonhote’s experience, communicated November 2nd, 1896:—
“The Hooded and Carrion-Crows are to be strictly avoided; the latter bird
when hand-reared is very tame and can articulate a few words, but has no
interesting actions or habits and scarcely moves the whole day. The former bird
(Grey Crow) is not only stupid, but dangerous, and is never satisﬁed till he has
the whole aviary to himself, having murdered the other inmates.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="260" y="2577"/>
	<Point x="2172" y="2577"/>
	<Point x="2172" y="2730"/>
	<Point x="260" y="2730"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* This bird has, however, been known to build among Rooks, but they do not appear to appreciate his
society.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r8">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1103" y="2357"/>
	<Point x="1103" y="2376"/>
	<Point x="1313" y="2376"/>
	<Point x="1313" y="2357"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
