<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667857">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T06:36:44</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:15</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667857.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="863" y="204"/>
	<Point x="1218" y="204"/>
	<Point x="1218" y="249"/>
	<Point x="863" y="249"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE WAXWING</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1915" y="217"/>
	<Point x="1971" y="217"/>
	<Point x="1971" y="260"/>
	<Point x="1915" y="260"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>19</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="117" y="327"/>
	<Point x="1970" y="327"/>
	<Point x="1970" y="506"/>
	<Point x="117" y="506"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>usually without the white tips to the inner webs of the primaries, and with smaller
wax-like terminations to the secondaries; the tips of the tail-feathers somewhat
narrower. The young are browner, and have no black on the throat.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="118" y="514"/>
	<Point x="1976" y="514"/>
	<Point x="1976" y="1496"/>
	<Point x="118" y="1496"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>This species appears in the breeding-season to haunt the more open portions
of forests of conifers and birch, but chieﬂy woods of pine, or larch, nesting in
colonies. The nest is a large open cup-shaped structure built upon the branch
of a tree, upon a foundation of twigs and reindeer moss, composed principally
of black hair-lichen, interwoven with slender twigs, bark, moss, and feathers, the
latter appearing most prominently in the lining. The eggs usually number from
ﬁve to six, rarely seven, and are described by Professor Newton, who owns the
greater part of the large series acquired by John Wolley (the discoverer of the
breeding-grounds of this species) as “delicate sea-green, sometimes fading to French
white, but often of a more or less pale-olive, and occasionally of a dull purplish-
grey. On this are almost always bold blotches, spots, and specks of deep brownish-
black, though sometimes the edges are blurred. Beneath these stronger markings
there is nearly always a series of blotches or streaks of greyish-lilac, and among
them well-deﬁned spots or specks of yellowish-brown are interspersed. In some
eggs the darkest markings are quite wanting, in others the ground is of a deep
olive colour.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="119" y="1515"/>
	<Point x="1973" y="1515"/>
	<Point x="1973" y="1760"/>
	<Point x="119" y="1760"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>According to Seebohm, who, in 1867, kept a pair of this species in a cage,
“They were remarkably silent birds; the only note I heard was a cir-ir-ir-ir-re,
very similar to a well-known note of the Blue-Tit. Occasionally this succession
of notes was repeated so rapidly as to form a trill like the song of the Redpole.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="115" y="1769"/>
	<Point x="1971" y="1769"/>
	<Point x="1971" y="2122"/>
	<Point x="115" y="2122"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the summer time the Waxwing appears to be largely, if not wholly insecti‐
vorous, crane-ﬂies seeming to constitute its favourite food; but later in the year
it devours great quantities of berries of juniper, privet, guelder-rose, as well as
hips and haws: it is especially fond of mistletoe berries. In the winter, when
Waxwings are very fat, they are said to be greatly esteemed by the Russians as
an article of food.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="109" y="2142"/>
	<Point x="1973" y="2142"/>
	<Point x="1973" y="2697"/>
	<Point x="109" y="2697"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Lord Lilford, in his “Birds of Northamptonshire,” speaks of “the chatter of
a party of Waxwings passing overhead whilst we were inspecting my aviary in
the pleasure-grounds at Lilford,” and he adds—“I am well acquainted with the
note of the Waxwing from having kept many of them in conﬁnement, a proceeding
which I cannot recommend, as they have no merit whatever except their beauty,
being dull, quarrelsome, greedy, and ﬁlthy to an incredible degree, and in most
instances dying from plethora after a short captivity. Hips and haws, currants,
raisins, (in fact, small fruit of all kinds) are voraciously devoured by these birds,
and appear to be their favourite food, but they will also eat chopped meat, hard-</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
