<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668144">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T23:06:54</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:39</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668144.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1019" y="219"/>
	<Point x="1341" y="219"/>
	<Point x="1341" y="282"/>
	<Point x="1019" y="282"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE MAGPIE</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="237" y="327"/>
	<Point x="2113" y="327"/>
	<Point x="2113" y="528"/>
	<Point x="237" y="528"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>it, as with buoyant but somewhat jerky ﬂight, it ﬂoats down some broad pheasant
drive, exhibiting its pied wings and superb tail to perfection; it, however, rarely
remains long in view, its aerial excursions being generally of short duration.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="235" y="537"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="537"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="1026"/>
	<Point x="235" y="1026"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although fond of woodland and forest, the Magpie is not strictly conﬁned to
them, for it often wanders through well timbered valleys, or even over moorland;
whilst in the pastures it may not unfrequently be observed upon the backs of
feeding cattle, searching for ticks and maggots. Referring to this habit Lord
Lilford observes:—“I am assured by an experienced tenant-farmer in our neighbour‐
hood that he considers this remedy worse than the disease, as the Magpies in the
search for maggots acquire a taste for beef, and cause hideous sores which are
diﬃcult to treat.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="237" y="1034"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1034"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1777"/>
	<Point x="237" y="1777"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Magpie is at times both restless and noisy, but chieﬂy when aware of
the approach of man whom it has learnt from sad experience to look upon with
suspicion. Naturally less shy than the Jay, it would doubtless soon be conﬁding
if mankind would but treat it more gently: it is indeed an ascertained fact, that
wherever it is not persecuted, this bird commonly builds its nest close to the
habitations of man, and in most conspicuous places. Even where it is not looked
upon with favour, this is sometimes the case, for in 1884, I noticed the unmistak‐
able nest of this species at the top of a lofty elm-tree within a hundred yards of
the house in which I was staying, at Upchurch, near Newington, Kent. The
tree formed one of a row along the end of a ﬁeld, and quite close to the main‐
line of the Chatham and Dover Railway. I also saw the nest close to the little
village of Bobbing in a small spinney.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="231" y="1784"/>
	<Point x="2117" y="1784"/>
	<Point x="2117" y="2217"/>
	<Point x="231" y="2217"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although half afraid to trust one, and ever on the alert, the Magpie often
keeps but a short distance ahead as one passes through its haunts, either in the
trees above, or on the ground; at one moment it will be peering and chattering
from a branch, the tail rising and falling, or opening and shutting, after the
manner of the South American Jays; now it will drop buoyantly down to the
scrub, whence it will appear upon the path, and then for a short space ﬂit down
the same to rise again to a branch and repeat the whole performance.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="2222"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="2222"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="2716"/>
	<Point x="226" y="2716"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Magpie is single-brooded and breeds early, usually constructing its nest
towards the end of March, though sometimes as late as May, and most frequently
placing it in the outer branches, though less often near the highest point of the
main stem: sometimes, however, tall, or even low hedges as well as thorn-bushes
are selected as a building site. J. B. Pilley, (“Zoologist” 1891, p. 352), observes
that, when he was a boy, he and his companions believed that there were two
species of Magpies, one building in a tree, the other in a hedge, and he says:—
“I can distinctly remember the sorry plight I sometimes presented after climbing</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="221"/>
	<Point x="371" y="221"/>
	<Point x="371" y="278"/>
	<Point x="226" y="278"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>160</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
