<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667959">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T06:47:07</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:26</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667959.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="983" y="207"/>
	<Point x="1309" y="207"/>
	<Point x="1309" y="302"/>
	<Point x="983" y="302"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SISKIN</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1997" y="228"/>
	<Point x="2095" y="228"/>
	<Point x="2095" y="309"/>
	<Point x="1997" y="309"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>67</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="333"/>
	<Point x="2090" y="336"/>
	<Point x="2084" y="781"/>
	<Point x="1232" y="784"/>
	<Point x="190" y="785"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>every tone and movement is full of animation and delight, as if it were beside
itself with pleasure; this is particularly the case in the nesting season, at which
time I have seen the male ﬂying slowly towards some topmost spray of a ﬁr-tree,
pouring forth his delightful little warbling song, which very much resembles that
of a Goldﬁnch, but is to my ears far sweeter. It very often sings when ﬂying,
but more frequently when perching on some ﬁr-tree top; indeed the Siskin in
spring seems more like a visitor from a happier world.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="190" y="789"/>
	<Point x="2087" y="787"/>
	<Point x="2082" y="1590"/>
	<Point x="190" y="1599"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Siskin usually places its nest high up, near the end of a lateral branch
of a ﬁr- or birch-tree, or even at the top against the main stem; but the nest is
also said to be sometimes built quite low down in spruce, furze, or juniper bushes,
though Seebohm was inclined to doubt the correctness of the records upon which
this statement is based, Naumann having asserted that the nest is always in con‐
ifers, seldom less than twenty-ﬁve feet from the ground. The nest itself is neatly
constructed of moss and rootlets, upon a slight foundation of heather and bents,
and the lining consists of vegetable down, horsehairs, and sometimes a few feathers.
The eggs number from ﬁve to six, and exactly resemble those of the Goldﬁnch
in size, colour, markings, and variations: they are bluish-green, usually pale;
spotted, dotted, and sometimes streaked with dark chocolate-brown, and with lilacine
greyish shell-markings; as with the eggs of all the typical Finches, they vary
considerably in size.*</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="191" y="1603"/>
	<Point x="2083" y="1597"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="1843"/>
	<Point x="1705" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="1684" y="1849"/>
	<Point x="1668" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="1408" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="1393" y="1848"/>
	<Point x="1377" y="1848"/>
	<Point x="1368" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="570" y="1846"/>
	<Point x="193" y="1845"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Like all the true Finches the hen bird builds the ﬁrst nest and incubates
alone, although the male as usual tries to help and only succeeds in hindering;
whether he works in earnest at the second nest I do not know: but, from his
close relationship to the Goldﬁnch, he should be capable of doing so.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="195" y="1848"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="1851"/>
	<Point x="2081" y="2605"/>
	<Point x="191" y="2601"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Siskin feeds largely on seeds of weeds and beech-mast; but during the
breeding season it eats a considerable number of aphides, and probably small green
caterpillars, milky, unripe seeds of groundsel, sow-thistle, and similar weeds; whilst
at all seasons, it is as mischievous as a Tit in destroying tender buds. In captivity
it eats the usual seeds, being especially fond of hemp and teasel, also soft food,
green food, and (although I do not approve of such food) it is as fond as the
Goldﬁnch and the whole of the Tits of picking a bone, clinging to it in all
positions, and behaving in every respect exactly like a Tit. The Siskin is one
of the most charming of all aviary birds, on account of its wonderfully conﬁding
nature. I turned a pair which I purchased in November, 1889, about three weeks
after their capture, into a large aviary; and, in three days, they had so thoroughly
learned to trust me, that they ﬂew into my hand and disputed over poppy-seed</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="206" y="2611"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="2611"/>
	<Point x="2085" y="2737"/>
	<Point x="206" y="2737"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* The characters given by Howard Saunders to distinguish eggs of the Siskin from those of the Goldﬁnch
are only individual; I have known a Canary lay eggs as blue as those of a Bullﬁnch in one nest; and in the
next, considerably larger and almost white eggs: this is characteristic of all Fringillinœ which lay bluish eggs.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
