<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668115">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T15:03:43</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:37</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668115.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="5"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="912" y="198"/>
	<Point x="1351" y="198"/>
	<Point x="1351" y="260"/>
	<Point x="912" y="260"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>FAMILY CORVIDÆ</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1960" y="214"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="214"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="267"/>
	<Point x="1960" y="267"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>147</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="841" y="421"/>
	<Point x="1414" y="421"/>
	<Point x="1414" y="490"/>
	<Point x="841" y="490"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>FAMILY CORVIDÆ.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="323" y="745"/>
	<Point x="322" y="598"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="598"/>
	<Point x="2052" y="971"/>
	<Point x="194" y="970"/>
	<Point x="195" y="745"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>HE Crows are generally characterized by their large size: in the form of
the bill they diﬀer considerably; but it seems to be invariably hard, with
the nostrils at the base, and usually concealed by feathers; the feet are
always strong and scutellated, with powerful curved claws; the middle toe shorter
than the tarsus, the outer and middle toes united at the base and often to the
ﬁrst joint; the tail has twelve feathers.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="193" y="979"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="979"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="1660"/>
	<Point x="193" y="1660"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The family is represented in the British Isles by ﬁve genera:—Pyrrhocorax;
in which the bill is slender, arched, pointed and compressed; the wings graduated,
with the fourth primary longest: Nucifraga; in which the bill is stout, straight,
and with swollen base; the wings graduated, but with the ﬁfth primary counting
from the front of wing longest: Garrulus; with stout compressed bill, straight
at the base; the crown with erectile crest; wings moderately long and rounded,
the fourth to sixth primaries nearly of equal length: Pica; with stout compressed
bill, straight at the base, arched towards the tip, near to which the edge of the
upper mandible is slightly emarginate; the wings short and rounded, with the
fourth or ﬁfth primary longest; the tail very long: Corvus; with bill nearly as
in Pica; the wings long and graduated, with the fourth primary longest.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="188" y="1667"/>
	<Point x="2057" y="1667"/>
	<Point x="2057" y="2156"/>
	<Point x="188" y="2156"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Crows are cosmopolitan: according to Seebohm they “are almost omni‐
vorous, and are found in most localities, however bare and sterile. They are birds
of powerful, though rather heavy ﬂight, and on the ground walk with ease.
Their notes are harsh and unmusical. They build bulky nests of sticks, moss,
roots, etc., in the branches of trees, on cliﬀs, and in holes in tree-trunks, walls,
and rocks. Their eggs are from four to eight in number, and vary from almost
white to green, and in one or two instances red, in ground-colour, spotted and
blotched with green of varying degrees of intensity.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="186" y="2162"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="2162"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="2597"/>
	<Point x="186" y="2597"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As pets the Corvidœ generally are favourites, on account of their intelligence,
the ease with which they can be tamed, their amusing tricks, their general hardiness,
omnivorous tendencies, and lastly the marvellous mimicking powers which some of
them possess: the chief drawbacks to keeping these birds are their natural tendency
to mischief and pilfering when allowed comparative liberty and the labour necessary
to keep them clean when caged: they are best kept separately in small ﬂights—
about three feet high, two feet wide, and seven feet long.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="drop-capital">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="197" y="592"/>
	<Point x="197" y="741"/>
	<Point x="319" y="741"/>
	<Point x="319" y="592"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>T</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
