<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668136">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T07:05:49</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:39</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668136.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1039" y="226"/>
	<Point x="1283" y="226"/>
	<Point x="1283" y="296"/>
	<Point x="1039" y="296"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE JAY</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="230" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2101" y="333"/>
	<Point x="2100" y="593"/>
	<Point x="229" y="593"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>brighter than the colouring of its back, and this colouring becomes permanent.
I only became aware of the fact after I had completed the rearing of a ﬁne young
bird which was given to me; but my statement has since been conﬁrmed by Mr.
Meade-Waldo and others.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="228" y="596"/>
	<Point x="2102" y="596"/>
	<Point x="2103" y="1091"/>
	<Point x="226" y="1097"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Not many years ago this was a tolerably common bird in the Kentish woods;
nevertheless I but rarely found its nest, not more than three or four times at
most. I can only suppose that, in that county, the Jay may have been so perse‐
cuted, that it has to some extent departed from its customary plan of building
low down; and, like the Magpie, has made its home in the inaccessible branches
of some lofty tree: that such a proceeding would not be unprecedented is clear
from the fact that Sterland described a nest which he found at the top of a beech
tree, ﬁfty or sixty feet from the ground.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="1099"/>
	<Point x="2103" y="1093"/>
	<Point x="2106" y="1531"/>
	<Point x="223" y="1534"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Jay is essentially a bird of the woods and is far more frequently heard
than seen on account of its extreme wariness; now and again you may come suddenly
upon it and catch a glimpse of its showy plumage as it ﬂaps irregularly across
some opening into the sheltering foliage, screaming harshly as it ﬂies—chaik, chaik,
chaik: indeed I once disturbed a company of ﬁve in a small clearing. The alarm
note often commences with a frightened sort of whine; it is very harsh arrgh,
arrgh.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="222" y="1538"/>
	<Point x="2108" y="1534"/>
	<Point x="2104" y="2728"/>
	<Point x="209" y="2725"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Seebohm gives a singularly accurate account of the habits of this bird in a
state of freedom:—“The Jay becomes noisiest in the evening; and its discordant
notes may then be heard together with those of the Pheasant and the Magpie.
Numbers of the birds call together, or answer each other from diﬀerent parts of
the cover, and, with the note of the Wood-Owl and the purr of the Nightjar, make
a concert sounding singularly uncanny amidst the gloom of the forest. The
ﬂight of the Jay is a somewhat laboured one, performed very irregularly and with
rapid beatings of the wings. The Jay’s peculiar ﬂight is seen to the greatest per‐
fection when the bird is ﬂying in the open; for in the thick cover they appear to
scurry oﬀ amongst the branches, anxious to conceal themselves as soon as possible.
In spring the Jay may sometimes be observed to ﬂy at a considerable elevation
above its native woods, and, suddenly closing its wings to shoot downwards like
an arrow into the cover below. Although capable of long-sustained ﬂight, in this
country it rarely ﬂies far, preferring to go from tree to tree or to pursue its way
through the tangled undergrowth. When perched in a tree the Jay sits well upright,
its tail sometimes wafted to and fro, its head constantly turned from side to side,
and its crest erected or depressed, its restless actions showing its wariness and
timidity at being so far from cover. When thus perched the Jay can sometimes
be approached very closely; and it is a noteworthy fact, that singularly beautiful</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="224" y="224"/>
	<Point x="348" y="224"/>
	<Point x="348" y="292"/>
	<Point x="224" y="292"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>156</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
