<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667991">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T12:20:26</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:29</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667991.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="953" y="216"/>
	<Point x="1273" y="216"/>
	<Point x="1273" y="287"/>
	<Point x="953" y="287"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE TWITE</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1976" y="212"/>
	<Point x="2050" y="212"/>
	<Point x="2050" y="308"/>
	<Point x="1976" y="308"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>83</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="186" y="346"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="346"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="474"/>
	<Point x="186" y="474"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>there is no such triﬂing with the second structure. Although a late breeder, not
commencing nidiﬁcation before the middle of May, the Twite is double-brooded.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="186" y="476"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="476"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="660"/>
	<Point x="186" y="660"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is probable, as in the case of allied species, that this bird feeds partly
upon small caterpillars, as well as the leaves and unripe seeds of weeds. In con‐
ﬁnement it is passionately fond of soft food.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="665"/>
	<Point x="2050" y="665"/>
	<Point x="2050" y="1288"/>
	<Point x="185" y="1288"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>From time to time I have had Twites brought to me by bird-catchers; and,
in 1889, I purchased two males and turned them loose in one of my cool aviaries:
they very soon became fairly tame, but nothing like so conﬁding as Redpolls;
they, nevertheless, sang from the ﬁrst. Most birds are selﬁsh, but very few are
so persistently greedy, and spiteful withal, as Twites: I had some Canaries in
the same aviary; and, as they had barely completed their moult, a saucer of egg-
food was daily placed in the aviary for their beneﬁt; no sooner, however, did the
Twites discover that egg was good, than they simply took possession of the saucer,
savagely attacking every Canary that attempted to come near it until their some‐
what voracious appetite was sated.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="184" y="1289"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="1289"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="1537"/>
	<Point x="184" y="1537"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the spring of the following year my Twites began to assume the rosy
colouring on the lower back and rump, but before they had fully developed it,
they caught septic enteritis from a sick Canary, and, early in June, both of them
died. I never cared to purchase others.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="179" y="1543"/>
	<Point x="2055" y="1541"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="2159"/>
	<Point x="180" y="2159"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the ﬁrst volume of the “Avicultural Magazine,” p. 118, Mr. G. C. Swailes,
of Beverley, Yorks., gives the following interesting account of his experiments
in breeding Twites in conﬁnement:—“A pair of Twites (Acanthis ﬂavirostris) have
this season bred and reared young in my small aviary, and as it is, I believe, a
rather uncommon occurrence, a few notes may be acceptable * * * * * *
The birds are a very interesting pair, both being abnormally coloured—the cock
about half white pied, and the hen pure white (the latter may be known to some
of my readers, as it has been exhibited at both the Palace and Aquarium shows).
They are kept with about half a dozen other Finches in an aviary quite out in
the country.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="180" y="2162"/>
	<Point x="2058" y="2160"/>
	<Point x="2059" y="2593"/>
	<Point x="178" y="2593"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The hen commenced to build on May 14th, and laid her ﬁrst egg on the
17th, laying altogether ﬁve eggs and sitting closely after the third was laid. I
did not again look at the eggs, but saw the old birds busy feeding on the 2nd
of June and following days. I looked in the nest on the 8th, hoping to ﬁnd some
ﬁne young birds, but the nest contained only one poor starved thing which died
on the following day: the weather was very stormy at the time they were hatched
and I think this was the cause of their doing so badly.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="177" y="2597"/>
	<Point x="2061" y="2595"/>
	<Point x="2063" y="2720"/>
	<Point x="175" y="2719"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>On the 15th I noticed that the hen had nearly completed another nest, and
she laid on the 16th and three following days: having a Redpoll nesting at the</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
