<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668151">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T07:07:36</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:40</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668151.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="896" y="203"/>
	<Point x="1258" y="203"/>
	<Point x="1258" y="278"/>
	<Point x="896" y="278"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE JACKDAW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1908" y="203"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="203"/>
	<Point x="2016" y="276"/>
	<Point x="1908" y="276"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>163</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="126" y="326"/>
	<Point x="2017" y="326"/>
	<Point x="2017" y="706"/>
	<Point x="126" y="706"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The upper parts of the male Jackdaw are glossy black with purple and green
reﬂections; the ear-coverts, nape and sides of neck ashy-grey inclining to white;
under parts dull black; bill and feet black, iris greyish-white. The female is
slightly smaller than the male and has a slightly smaller and duller grey patch
on the nape; her bill is also a triﬂe shorter. The young are dull black, the
grey patch very feebly indicated.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="120" y="711"/>
	<Point x="2018" y="711"/>
	<Point x="2018" y="2390"/>
	<Point x="120" y="2390"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>There are few places where the Jackdaw cannot ﬁnd a home: coming from
the Continent to England, this bird may be seen in numbers ﬂying in and out of
holes in the cliﬀs of Dover, its incessant cries chack, chack, being a welcome sound;
so also in country or town, in ruined castle or modern palace the Jackdaw is
everywhere to be seen. I must confess that I like the Jackdaw: he is a bird
with considerable sense of humour, and (in spite of much persecution) he seems
to bear no malice. The late Lord Lilford, however, could ﬁnd nothing good to
say of him: the following being some of his remarks respecting the Jackdaw in
his “Birds of Northamptonshire”:—“This amusing but most pernicious bird is
extremely common in our county, and probably only too well-known to most of
our readers. In the hollow trees about the park and pleasure-grounds of Lilford
they used to swarm at the breeding-season, till we found it absolutely necessary
to wage war upon them in the interests of our garden, poultry, and game, to say
nothing of those of the Barn Owl, a species for which we have always entertained
a sincere respect and aﬀection. The Daws not only carried oﬀ numbers of young
chickens, pheasants, and partridges, and committed havoc among our green-peas
and other vegetables, but in several instances, to our knowledge, took possession
of the Owls’ nests, destroyed their eggs, and piled up their own nests in the cavities
selected by the harmless and most useful bird of night; occasionally, however, the
tables are turned, as we have previously mentioned when treating of the Barn Owl.
For these misdemeanours we have for some years past made a practice of shooting
the old Jackdaws and destroying their nests and eggs wherever we found them,
with the result of decided beneﬁt to ourselves and our neighbours. The Jackdaw
disputes the palm for noisy and obtrusive impudence with the House-Sparrow, and
does not, to our knowledge, compensate us in any way for his misdoings. That
the Daw fulﬁls his duties in the great scheme of nature I do not deny, but must
confess that I am unable to discover what they may be.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="125" y="2398"/>
	<Point x="2022" y="2398"/>
	<Point x="2022" y="2636"/>
	<Point x="125" y="2636"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Seebohm, however, although he admits that it levies blackmail on the Gulls,
says of the Jackdaw:—“It is quite as harmless a bird as the Rook, and at certain
seasons of the year it is very useful. You have but to watch its actions in the
ﬁelds to be convinced of this.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="242" y="2643"/>
	<Point x="2006" y="2643"/>
	<Point x="2006" y="2710"/>
	<Point x="242" y="2710"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Jackdaw’s ﬂight is like himself, strong, but somewhat purposeless; he</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
