<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667834">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T01:04:22</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:12</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667834.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="308" y="262"/>
	<Point x="342" y="262"/>
	<Point x="342" y="302"/>
	<Point x="308" y="302"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>8</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="862" y="251"/>
	<Point x="1540" y="251"/>
	<Point x="1540" y="299"/>
	<Point x="862" y="299"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE GREAT GREY SHRIKE.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="275" y="376"/>
	<Point x="2128" y="376"/>
	<Point x="2128" y="806"/>
	<Point x="275" y="806"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>branch of an olive, apple, pear, oak, or ﬁr tree; it is bulky, and large as that of
a Blackbird, and is formed of twigs, bents, dead leaves, green grass, and moss;
the lining consisting of rootlets, wool, hair, and feathers. The eggs number from
ﬁve to seven, usually ﬁve, and vary from creamy to bluish white, with lighter or
darker olivaceous spots and blotches, frequently forming a well-deﬁned zone just
above the middle, and accompanied by lilac-grey shell-markings; sometimes
they form a large patch at one end (usually the larger one).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="274" y="812"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="812"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="990"/>
	<Point x="274" y="990"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Nidiﬁcation as a rule commences about the middle of May; incubation lasts
ﬁfteen days; and, during the rearing of the young, this species is most courageous
in their defence, driving away even the Crow-family from the vicinity of its nest.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="270" y="999"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="999"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="1367"/>
	<Point x="270" y="1367"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Gätke says:—“This bird, though very cautious in general, is yet not unfre-
quently caught in the throstle bush; that, however, such a fate is well deserved,
is shown by the discovery of many a poor little Redbreast with its brains hacked
out, the work of this ruthless aggressor. I have even on one occasion seen a
Blackbird, as it was hastening along over the grass, pounced upon by one of these
daring robbers, and succumb, after a short struggle, to the bites of his assailant.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="262" y="1374"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1374"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1929"/>
	<Point x="262" y="1929"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Lord Lilford says that about the end of December, 1880, he received a ﬁne
young bird of this species alive: it had been taken by means of bird-lime near
Glendow, on November 19th; he kept this bird alive for some months. Herr
Mathias Rausch (Geﬁederte Welt, 1891, p. 475) observes that this bird is not of
the slightest value for aviculture as a singer, for although he both mocks well
and sings industriously, he, by his call-notes, makes the other singers crazy with
anxiety and fear, and thereby disturbs them in their song. “One can only ﬁnd
it caged in the possession of peculiar fanciers, who mostly aim at completeness, in
respect of all birds belonging to this category.”*</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="265" y="1939"/>
	<Point x="2114" y="1939"/>
	<Point x="2114" y="2368"/>
	<Point x="265" y="2368"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>From a long study of birds in conﬁnement, I should imagine that Herr Rausch
speaks here theoretically, and not from experience: if the cry of a Shrike in a
cage is calculated to terrify a small song-bird in another cage, surely the small
song-birds of South America ought to be alarmed by the cries of the Blue-bearded
Jay, or even those of the Sulphur Tyrant; yet they pay no more heed to them than
to the calls of perfectly innocent birds: I believe that predaceous species are
recognized by sight, more readily than by their voice.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="376" y="2706"/>
	<Point x="1817" y="2706"/>
	<Point x="1817" y="2749"/>
	<Point x="376" y="2749"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* I imagine his meaning to be that they keep all Passeres, whether interesting or not.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
