<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667897">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-07T21:40:43</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:19</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667897.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="925" y="192"/>
	<Point x="1272" y="192"/>
	<Point x="1272" y="247"/>
	<Point x="925" y="247"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE MARTIN</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1957" y="202"/>
	<Point x="2040" y="202"/>
	<Point x="2040" y="260"/>
	<Point x="1957" y="260"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>37</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="147" y="315"/>
	<Point x="2045" y="315"/>
	<Point x="2045" y="565"/>
	<Point x="147" y="565"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>to strengthen its walls is another puzzle, for the additional stability which it gives
to a Swallow's nest is so considerable; that, taking a metal dipper ﬁlled with hay
to the top of a chimney, I have only had to lower the edge of the metal pan
below the nest and jerk it upwards, to secure the nest uninjured.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="160" y="567"/>
	<Point x="2047" y="567"/>
	<Point x="2048" y="1187"/>
	<Point x="954" y="1191"/>
	<Point x="160" y="1186"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The food of the Martin consists wholly of insects, which it obtains on the
wing; in conﬁnement, however, it readily feeds upon the usual soft food. In the
ﬁrst week of July, 1891, my colleague, Mr. W. R. Ogilvie Grant obtained a nest
of four House-Martins about a week old, and gave them to me. Following out
the mistaken notions of many aviculturists I at ﬁrst fed these young birds partly
upon raw rump-steak ﬁnely minced; but I also gave them a mixture of carefully
selected ants' cocoons, and preserved yolk of egg, ground up in a mortar with
maizena wafers, the whole carefully mixed together, and slightly damped. Upon
this diet all four attained their full size, after which they refused the raw meat,
but continued to eat the mixture greedily.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="145" y="1195"/>
	<Point x="2045" y="1195"/>
	<Point x="2045" y="2380"/>
	<Point x="145" y="2380"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>I kept these birds in a basket ﬁlled with hay, and several times each day they
were taken out and encouraged to ﬂy about the room; but now they began to
object to return to the close conﬁnement of their basket; therefore I purchased a
large cage, hung up a cocoa-nut nest lined with ﬂannel in one corner, and taught
them to retire to it every evening, or whenever they appeared to feel the cold.
At the end of a month the Martins were able to feed themselves, and, like all the
Hirundinidœ when accustomed to soft food, they ate far more than was good for
them. I now tried a change of diet, giving “Abrahams' Food for Nightingales,”
damped ants' cocoons, cut up mealworms, and ﬂies; but it was of no use, for three
of them soon died of plethora, and probably, in part, owing to insuﬃcient exercise,
although we did our best to encourage them to exert themselves in various ways.
One of our plans was to put all four on the ground at one end of the room, then
run to the other end and call them: this was the signal for a most comical race,
in which at ﬁrst they ran at a surprising rate though very awkwardly; but, as
they became excited in the race, used their wings, and ﬁnished with a series of
astounding leaps, ﬁnally ﬂying on to our arms, and either running up our sleeves,
nestling down in the hollowed palms of our hands, or perching on our shoulders.
My son used often to hold one up in his hand, and it invariably sprang up and
pecked his nose, but only one of the four would do this.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="147" y="2385"/>
	<Point x="2057" y="2385"/>
	<Point x="2057" y="2630"/>
	<Point x="147" y="2630"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although naturally so greedy, our Martins would always leave their food
and ﬂy to us when called; they could not, therefore, be accused, like most cage-
birds, of cupboard-love; they were also unlike other birds in their fondness for
being handled and stroked.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="256" y="2635"/>
	<Point x="2037" y="2635"/>
	<Point x="2037" y="2695"/>
	<Point x="247" y="2695"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>My fourth bird lived until the morning of September 18th, and became a</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="269" y="2710"/>
	<Point x="384" y="2710"/>
	<Point x="384" y="2743"/>
	<Point x="269" y="2743"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r16" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1715" y="2708"/>
	<Point x="1755" y="2708"/>
	<Point x="1755" y="2744"/>
	<Point x="1715" y="2744"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>L</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
