<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667873">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T22:38:21</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:17</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667873.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="830" y="204"/>
	<Point x="1386" y="204"/>
	<Point x="1386" y="265"/>
	<Point x="830" y="265"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE PIED FLYCATCHER</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1955" y="220"/>
	<Point x="2013" y="220"/>
	<Point x="2013" y="273"/>
	<Point x="1955" y="273"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>27</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="126" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2033" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2033" y="764"/>
	<Point x="563" y="768"/>
	<Point x="126" y="764"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>spot, and before I had seen any other description of it, recall the song to my
memory—the short notes at the beginning, the rather fragmentary and hesitating
character of the strain, and the little coda or ﬁnish, which reminded me of the
Chaﬃnch, but all this will have no meaning to my readers. There is but one
way of learning a bird's song, and that is by listening to it in solitude again and
again, until you have associated it in your mind, with the form, and habits, and
haunts of the singer.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="140" y="773"/>
	<Point x="2013" y="779"/>
	<Point x="2005" y="1203"/>
	<Point x="1433" y="1205"/>
	<Point x="657" y="1206"/>
	<Point x="136" y="1201"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Gätke states that the Pied Flycatcher “visits Heligoland in larger numbers
than any of its near relatives. It is especially abundant during the autumn
migration, returning from its nesting quarters as early as the beginning of August,
if the weather is ﬁne and warm, and the wind from the south or south-east.”
Why this bird should migrate before scarcity of food or cold compel it to do so,
it is diﬃcult to understand; probably the tendency has been inherited, and points
back to some remote period when the summers of Europe were of short duration.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="145" y="1210"/>
	<Point x="2007" y="1216"/>
	<Point x="2010" y="1700"/>
	<Point x="1156" y="1708"/>
	<Point x="1102" y="1708"/>
	<Point x="219" y="1706"/>
	<Point x="136" y="1705"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The food of this species consists largely of insects, but it rarely, if ever,
pursues them in the air like the Spotted Flycatcher, preferring to watch from the
end of a branch, and pounce suddenly down upon them; it is not, therefore, sur‐
prising that among the pellets of undigested matter ejected by this, as by other
insectivorous birds, wing-cases of small beetles predominate; it is, however, said
to pick ﬂies and gnats from leaves upon which they have settled, and to eat worms.
Later in the year, as currants, raspberries, elderberries, etc., become ripe, the Pied
Flycatcher is said to add them to its dietary.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="144" y="1713"/>
	<Point x="2010" y="1718"/>
	<Point x="2004" y="2708"/>
	<Point x="140" y="2703"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Far more beautiful than its Spotted relative, and with a much better idea of
music, it is no wonder that, where opportunity offers, this species is prized as a
cage-bird; yet I have never seen one exhibited in England; though in Germany
the Pied Flycatcher has put in an appearance at the exhibitions of the “Ornis”
Society. Being so much more local in Great Britain than the Spotted Flycatcher,
this species is much less frequently obtained at the right age for hand-rearing:
when once obtained, however, Swaysland assures us that it is far more easy to
keep than the commoner species, and may be turned either into cage or aviary,
and fed in the same way as Warblers, or as the Nightingale. Doubtless the food
recommended for M. grisola by Mr. Louis Bonhote (Avicultural Magazine, Vol. I,
p. 58) would answer equally well for this species; he says:—“In captivity, they
should be fed on ants' eggs, and hard-boiled eggs, mixed in equal parts, and as
many mealworms as their keeper can afford to give them. They become very tame,
and will rise in the air and catch mealworms as they are thrown to them. In
catching a mealworm, they leave the perch and hover in the air, waiting for the
mealworm to drop, and catch it as it passes them; if they should miss it, they</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
