<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668192">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-09T04:13:01</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:43</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668192.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="947" y="183"/>
	<Point x="1347" y="183"/>
	<Point x="1347" y="252"/>
	<Point x="947" y="252"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SKY-LARK</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="200" y="307"/>
	<Point x="2083" y="307"/>
	<Point x="2083" y="685"/>
	<Point x="200" y="685"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>the second feather white on the outer web only: under parts buﬃsh-white, spotted
and streaked with blackish-brown on the throat, breast and ﬂanks; bill dark
brown above, paler below; feet yellowish-brown; iris hazel. The female is rather
smaller than the male, and has shorter wings, but does not diﬀer in plumage:
young birds have broad buﬀ tips to the feathers. After the autumn moult both
sexes are more tawny in colouring.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="204" y="690"/>
	<Point x="2088" y="690"/>
	<Point x="2088" y="1250"/>
	<Point x="204" y="1250"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In order to tell the sex of the Sky-Lark, the London bird-dealers take the bird
in the left hand with the tail towards them, and with the right hand draw down
the wing until the point of the ﬁrst long primary touches the tip of the outer-
most tail-feather: the wing of the male being distinctly longer than that of the
female, the so-called “shoulder” then appears to be much more angular in the
former than in the latter sex. I have seen considerable numbers of birds thus
tested, the males being caged and the females returned to the catchers, and I
never knew the test to fail: but females are rarely forwarded by experienced bird-
catchers, most of them being killed at the nets and sold to the poulterers.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="200" y="1254"/>
	<Point x="2092" y="1254"/>
	<Point x="2092" y="1561"/>
	<Point x="200" y="1561"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Although abundant enough on moors and commons, downs, grassy cliﬀs, and
even mountains, the Sky-Lark certainly prefers arable land, pastures, and parks:
it seems especially to delight in ﬁelds of clover: it shuns all places thickly
studded with trees, such as woods, copses, and plantations, but is almost always
to be met with in country cemeteries.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="207" y="1568"/>
	<Point x="2096" y="1568"/>
	<Point x="2100" y="2250"/>
	<Point x="207" y="2250"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Excepting when in pursuit of another individual of its own species, the ﬂight
of the Sky-Lark does not strike one as being particularly rapid; it is somewhat
undulating, and there is a ﬂuttering motion, even when it is crossing a ﬁeld, which
is very characteristic. The male, when soaring, always commences its upward
ﬂight with this butterﬂy-like hovering action, and sometimes it is continued until
it reaches its highest elevation; at other times it rises obliquely and rapidly, its
song the whole time ﬁtting its movements: in its descent it sometimes drops
abruptly perhaps for forty or ﬁfty feet, pauses a second and drops again, making
perhaps three or four stages in its fall, until, as it nears the ground, it ﬂutters
round in a half-circle to the earth; each drop being accompanied by the ﬁnishing
shrill whee, whee, whee of its song: often it comes down with a wide graceful sweep.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="211" y="2257"/>
	<Point x="2102" y="2257"/>
	<Point x="2102" y="2688"/>
	<Point x="211" y="2688"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest is placed in a depression in the ground, generally amongst growing
crops, often merely sheltered on one side by an overhanging tuft of coarse grass
or other vegetation, and sometimes without any shelter whatever; a singular nest
with a kind of lid formed of water-weed, which was pointed out to me by a
shepherd in the Isle of Sheppy, is described in my “Handbook.” The nest itself
is more or less loosely constructed of dried bents and dead grass, and lined with
ﬁner grass-stalks. The eggs number from four to ﬁve, and sometimes three may</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="216" y="204"/>
	<Point x="321" y="204"/>
	<Point x="321" y="254"/>
	<Point x="216" y="254"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>184</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
