<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00667905">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:11:33</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:20</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00667905.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="864" y="187"/>
	<Point x="1361" y="187"/>
	<Point x="1361" y="248"/>
	<Point x="864" y="248"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SAND-MARTIN</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1967" y="203"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="203"/>
	<Point x="2041" y="254"/>
	<Point x="1967" y="254"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>41</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="167" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2054" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2054" y="435"/>
	<Point x="167" y="435"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>commences late in August, and sometimes continues up to the middle of
October.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="154" y="441"/>
	<Point x="2070" y="441"/>
	<Point x="2070" y="2019"/>
	<Point x="154" y="2019"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As a cage-bird the Sand-Martin cannot be commended:—when on a nesting
excursion in Kent, in July, 1887, a family of ﬁve little Sand-Martins was brought
to me: as the birds were too young to let ﬂy, I determined to try and keep them
as pets, but I found it a harder task than I had anticipated to induce them to
open their mouths for the food (Abrahams' Nightingale Mixture) which I gave
them. However, after nearly a week's perseverance, my wife and a girl who then
assisted in looking after my birds, succeeded in persuading four of them to open
their mouths when food was oﬀered. All ﬁve were then in excellent health, though
rather too fat: they were very pretty, and when sitting on one's ﬁnger, looked
exactly like diminutive hawks. Unfortunately, although by this time the Martins
were well able to ﬂy, they could only be induced to do so if taken into a room
where their food was not in sight. In less than a fortnight they could feed them-
selves, and after that they would eat incessantly, swallowing such huge mouthfuls
of the soft food, that it seemed marvellous where they could stow it all away:
then they would fall asleep, sitting upon the edge of the food-pot, and remain in
a state of stupor for perhaps half-an-hour, when they would wake up and begin
to gorge again. Naturally this life did not agree with birds whose nature it is to
be incessantly on the move, and who get their food slowly and in minute morsels;
they grew rapidly thinner and weaker, staggered in their walk as if drunken, and
dropped oﬀ one by one, until, in just over three weeks from the time when I
received them, the last of them died. Possibly, if it had been practicable for me
to be at home to attend to them, I might have given these birds their food at
stated intervals, and compelled them to take exercise; in which case, perhaps their
lives might have been prolonged: but Sand-Martins are not suitable birds for
the aviculturist.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="281" y="2709"/>
	<Point x="393" y="2709"/>
	<Point x="393" y="2740"/>
	<Point x="281" y="2740"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1710" y="2700"/>
	<Point x="1763" y="2700"/>
	<Point x="1763" y="2738"/>
	<Point x="1710" y="2738"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>M</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r7">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="998" y="2287"/>
	<Point x="1201" y="2287"/>
	<Point x="1201" y="2306"/>
	<Point x="998" y="2306"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
