<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668122">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T23:04:23</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:38</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668122.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="240" y="324"/>
	<Point x="2137" y="324"/>
	<Point x="2137" y="1323"/>
	<Point x="240" y="1323"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>years took a ﬁrst prize at the Crystal Palace which seemed to have been ﬁve
years old in 1887, ten years old in 1890, and twelve years old in 1891; since
which time it became contented with a twelve-month year: possibly there may
have been three cock birds; but, with a species the nestlings of which must be
diﬃcult to secure, this would seem less probable than that an error had occurred
in stating the age, due perhaps to the fact of no record having been kept to
which reference could be made. That the Chough can be induced to breed in a
state of partial domestication has been proved by Lady Nevill (“Zoologist,” 1882,
p. 431); she says:—“For years when I lived at Dangstein I kept Choughs (P.
graculus) able to ﬂy where they liked. They once attempted to make a nest in a
stoke-hole, but were disturbed, and never did so again. On my removal to East
Sussex I brought the Choughs (two pairs) with me, and the next year one pair
made their nest in a tower attached to the house, and laid three eggs; but they
did not sit well, and the eggs were not hatched: two of them were pulled out of
the nest. The one pair drove the others away, for when they ﬁrst came they all
roosted in the tower.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="244" y="1334"/>
	<Point x="2140" y="1334"/>
	<Point x="2140" y="1721"/>
	<Point x="244" y="1721"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It seems extremely probable that breeding experiments with one pair would
be successful. There is, however, one very strong objection to Choughs in
captivity: I understand that my friend Mr. Reginald Phillipps, a very well-known
aviculturist, at one time attempted to keep these birds; but the noise which they
made was so appalling that the neighbours were driven to the verge of madness,
and he wisely parted with his pets before any tragic climax had been arrived at.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1010" y="209"/>
	<Point x="1359" y="209"/>
	<Point x="1359" y="273"/>
	<Point x="1010" y="273"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE CHOUGH</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="253" y="224"/>
	<Point x="253" y="288"/>
	<Point x="372" y="288"/>
	<Point x="372" y="224"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>150</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r7">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1081" y="2189"/>
	<Point x="1081" y="2229"/>
	<Point x="1300" y="2229"/>
	<Point x="1300" y="2189"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
