<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668183">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T01:41:47</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:42</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668183.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="932" y="229"/>
	<Point x="1201" y="229"/>
	<Point x="1201" y="292"/>
	<Point x="932" y="292"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE ROOK</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1911" y="243"/>
	<Point x="1995" y="243"/>
	<Point x="1995" y="297"/>
	<Point x="1911" y="297"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>179</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="134" y="346"/>
	<Point x="1996" y="347"/>
	<Point x="1995" y="477"/>
	<Point x="135" y="476"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>increasing, occasionally wandering to the Outer Hebrides and now breeding as
far north as the Orkneys and Shetlands.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="134" y="482"/>
	<Point x="1996" y="479"/>
	<Point x="1998" y="915"/>
	<Point x="132" y="915"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The male Rook is black, glossed with purple, most brightly on the upper
parts. From the base of the bill is a bare grey warty patch, extending over the
chin and upper part of the throat. Bill and feet black; iris brown. The female
is slightly smaller and less glossy than the male. The young bird is still less
glossy and has the base of the bill covered, as in the Carrion-Crow, with
bristly feathers; it may be distinguished by its more slender bill and the deep ﬂesh-
colour of the inside of the mouth, this, however, changes to slate-colour with age.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="131" y="916"/>
	<Point x="1999" y="917"/>
	<Point x="2001" y="1409"/>
	<Point x="1513" y="1412"/>
	<Point x="741" y="1412"/>
	<Point x="728" y="1411"/>
	<Point x="128" y="1409"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In England the Rook is a useful bird so long as it can obtain a suﬃcient
quantity of insects and their larvæ to support it and its oﬀspring; but when,
owing to protracted drought it cannot obtain these, it becomes somewhat
mischievous after the fashion of its congeners. In Scotland, where pastures are
somewhat limited, it is dreaded and detested almost as much as the Carrion-Crow.
It is certain that when pressed by hunger it will sacriﬁce weak birds to satisfy
its craving for food; for, as noted in my “Handbook” I have on several
occasions witnessed this predatory habit in severe wintry weather.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="127" y="1412"/>
	<Point x="746" y="1415"/>
	<Point x="1545" y="1415"/>
	<Point x="2001" y="1413"/>
	<Point x="1996" y="1916"/>
	<Point x="126" y="1914"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Rook is essentially a gregarious bird and haunts well-cultivated districts,
preferably where tall trees are numerous and pastures are large; here he may be
seen day after day busily feeding on snails or digging for worms, leather-jackets
and other noxious grubs; in the fallows, whilst he doubtless swallows a little
grain, he does incalculable good by destroying wire-worms and larvæ of cock‐
chafers, whilst in the turnip-ﬁelds he not only devours such examples of the
latter grubs as he can ﬁnd, but does considerable execution upon the dreaded
and destructive caterpillar of a common moth (Agrotis segetum).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="126" y="1916"/>
	<Point x="1998" y="1918"/>
	<Point x="2003" y="2729"/>
	<Point x="121" y="2733"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nests are generally placed in the upper branches of tall trees; either in
copses, plantations, pleasure-grounds, parks, or when planted in rows bounding
the margin of a pasture, or forming an avenue over a country road; but
Stevenson rightly says:—“Though for the most part selecting the tallest trees,
and placing their nest near the upper branches, they will build also on low
Scotch ﬁrs, in the most exposed situations,” and he adds:—“A still more novel
site has also been chosen by a few pairs at Spixworth Park, where, for the last
two or three seasons, they have built in the tops of some ﬁne laurustinus bushes,
about twelve or fourteen feet from the ground, and others in a dwarf ilex, close
to a ﬂight of stone steps, connecting one part of the garden with the other, yet
so low down that the feeding of the young was plainly visible from the windows
of the hall.” When a rookery is well established, the birds are not easily
persuaded to abandon it, excepting for private reasons of their own; moreover the</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
