<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668184">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T09:41:55</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:42</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668184.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="224" y="170"/>
	<Point x="332" y="170"/>
	<Point x="332" y="230"/>
	<Point x="224" y="230"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>180</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1023" y="161"/>
	<Point x="1310" y="161"/>
	<Point x="1310" y="228"/>
	<Point x="1023" y="228"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE ROOK</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="232" y="284"/>
	<Point x="2114" y="275"/>
	<Point x="2113" y="467"/>
	<Point x="232" y="476"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>continual noises of a great city do not seem to disturb them at all, as is evident
from the fact that Rooks still build and breed in the old trees which have been
left standing in the busiest parts of London.*</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="232" y="477"/>
	<Point x="2114" y="470"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="1219"/>
	<Point x="226" y="1219"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The nest is usually commenced or repaired early in March, but after
unusually mild winters building operations sometimes commence much earlier.
After the exceptionally open winter of 1895-6 I saw several young Rooks sitting
just outside the nests in which they had been hatched as early as the 6th March,
whilst I had noticed the Rooks in a rookery close to my house repairing their
nests in January, and in February a pair daily visited my garden for worms: a
friend of mine living at Dulwich ﬁrst directed my attention to the early pre‐
parations for nesting made by these birds, assuring me in January that he had
seen a pair of Rooks carrying sticks up to their nest. In the “Feathered World”
for April 24th, 1896, Mr. W. N. Rushen says:— “I saw two young Rooks near
Wanstead Park, on April 8th, which were as strong on the wing as their parents;
and, to be as forward as this, they must have left the nest for some weeks.”†</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="1221"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1220"/>
	<Point x="2115" y="1721"/>
	<Point x="226" y="1722"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The structure is usually very compact, formed of strong sticks and twigs,
plastered with mud, lined with turf, straw, roots, and sometimes moss, dead
leaves, and feathers. The eggs number from three to ﬁve and vary considerably
both in form and colouring, exhibiting similar forms to those of the Carrion-
Crow; they are, however, noticeably smaller. The ground-colour varies from
pale blue to green, and is lighter or darker in diﬀerent nests; the spotting is
olive-brown, ﬁne and sparse, or coarser and thickly distributed over the entire
surface and sometimes with a few larger deep brown blotches or streaks.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="225" y="1723"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1724"/>
	<Point x="2116" y="1843"/>
	<Point x="224" y="1847"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Of the eggs ﬁgured on our plate, ﬁgs. 241 and 242 are from my own
collection, and 243 and 244 from that of Mr. A. B. Farn’s.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="225" y="1849"/>
	<Point x="2118" y="1845"/>
	<Point x="2117" y="2283"/>
	<Point x="711" y="2285"/>
	<Point x="224" y="2284"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>When the young ﬁrst leave the nest they are awkward and weak on their
legs, sitting huddled on a branch with their heads well down between their
shoulders; as the wind sways the branch they tip forwards, and have to open
their short wings to recover their balance; but, after daily short excursions
from branch to branch, they gradually gather strength and conﬁdence, until
ﬁnally they are able to accompany their parents to the ﬁelds and get their
ﬁrst lesson in ﬁnding food for themselves.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="223" y="2286"/>
	<Point x="2118" y="2286"/>
	<Point x="2118" y="2477"/>
	<Point x="223" y="2476"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>To those who have not noticed the methods by which the various species
of Crows are taught by their parents, I cannot do better than recommend the
admirable account given by Mrs. Olive Thorne Miller in her fascinating book</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="224" y="2478"/>
	<Point x="2118" y="2479"/>
	<Point x="2119" y="2571"/>
	<Point x="224" y="2576"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* Sometimes the nest is said to be placed on chimneys, ornaments of church spires, and rarely on the
ground.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="223" y="2578"/>
	<Point x="2121" y="2574"/>
	<Point x="2122" y="2650"/>
	<Point x="223" y="2654"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>+ Mr. Rushen was well-known to readers of that paper as one of its most reliable contributors; a keen
student and enthusiastic lover of our British Birds.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
