<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668224">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T14:46:12</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668224.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="6"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r10" index="7"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="196" y="209"/>
	<Point x="300" y="209"/>
	<Point x="300" y="261"/>
	<Point x="196" y="261"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>200</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="896" y="193"/>
	<Point x="1370" y="193"/>
	<Point x="1370" y="258"/>
	<Point x="896" y="258"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE SHORE-LARK</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="203" y="312"/>
	<Point x="2078" y="320"/>
	<Point x="2080" y="500"/>
	<Point x="203" y="503"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In summer the Shore-Lark inhabits the dry sandy plains and rocky hills of
the tundras, only approaching the rivers to drink. Seebohm says that it seems to
be entirely a ground bird, and he never saw it either on a tree or a bush.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="187" y="509"/>
	<Point x="2077" y="509"/>
	<Point x="2077" y="935"/>
	<Point x="187" y="935"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Everyone speaks well of the song of the Shore-Lark, for although it is short
and not very varied it is full of melody. It is sung by the bird not only when
on the earth—but, as with the Sky-Lark, much more frequently when the bird is
soaring in the air. At such times it is said to atone for the brevity of its song
by repeating it over and over again: this is practically what Alauda arvensis does
if you take the trouble to listen to him attentively. The call-note is described
as loud and clear.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="187" y="941"/>
	<Point x="2077" y="943"/>
	<Point x="2073" y="1497"/>
	<Point x="187" y="1503"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>As is the case with all our Larks, this species forms its nest in a slight
depression in the earth or among stones; sometimes entirely unprotected, but at
other times under the shelter of rushes. The nest, owing to the country where
it is constructed, naturally diﬀers somewhat in its materials from those of the
Larks with which we are familiar in England; externally it is similar, being
formed of dead grasses, bents, etc.; but internally it is lined with willow-down
and reindeer hair. The eggs number from four to ﬁve, rarely three (the latter
probably not representing a full clutch) and chieﬂy diﬀer from those of the Sky-
Lark in their generally more olive tint.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="180" y="1509"/>
	<Point x="2077" y="1509"/>
	<Point x="2077" y="2003"/>
	<Point x="180" y="2003"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>To show how easily this apparently conspicuous species may be overlooked,
Mr. Fenwick Hole, in the “Field,” for Nov. 19th, 1864, recorded the fact of his
shooting a pair, of which he only secured one, under the impression that they
were common Sky-Larks. He says “I was only led to shoot at them at all from
a desire to try my big duck gun at such small objects on the ground; you may,
therefore, judge of my surprise, when picking up the dead specimen, at my double
stroke of good luck—ﬁrstly, chancing to alight on such a rarity; and secondly,
ﬁring at it at all.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="2007"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2007"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2252"/>
	<Point x="185" y="2252"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Speaking of three specimens shot out of a ﬂock of about twenty at Lowestoft,
in February, 1865, the late Henry Stevenson says:—“The contents of their crops
* * * appeared to consist of seeds of Polygonaceœ and the chrysalis of some
small insect.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="192" y="2257"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2257"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2440"/>
	<Point x="192" y="2440"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The food of this Lark consists very largely of seeds, although in the summer
insects, their larvæ, and pupæ, as well (doubtless) as spiders are eaten; it also
devours small mollusca and crustacea cast up on the sea-shore.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="192" y="2444"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2444"/>
	<Point x="2075" y="2565"/>
	<Point x="192" y="2565"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Being both tame, beautiful, and musical, the Shore-Lark is often caged; and
of late years, it has frequently been exhibited at bird shows.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="180" y="2568"/>
	<Point x="2076" y="2568"/>
	<Point x="2076" y="2695"/>
	<Point x="180" y="2695"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Herr Gätke observes:—“On account of its pleasing appearance I have kept
one of these birds for years in a cage. The song, though by no means loud, is</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
