<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668169">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-10T07:09:31</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:41</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668169.tif" imageWidth="2293" imageHeight="3062">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="887" y="242"/>
	<Point x="1398" y="242"/>
	<Point x="1398" y="324"/>
	<Point x="887" y="324"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE CARRION-CROW</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1976" y="253"/>
	<Point x="2071" y="253"/>
	<Point x="2071" y="315"/>
	<Point x="1976" y="315"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>173</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="203" y="353"/>
	<Point x="2101" y="360"/>
	<Point x="2104" y="680"/>
	<Point x="204" y="684"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>combined attack, otherwise the young chicks of pheasants and partridges would
indeed fare badly. Lord Lilford observes:—“ We have not a word to say in
defence of the Carrion-Crow. His habits appear to us to be purely noxious, and
neither his personal appearance, voice, or manners in captivity oﬀers anything in
extenuation of his natural evil propensities.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="204" y="686"/>
	<Point x="2102" y="683"/>
	<Point x="2101" y="932"/>
	<Point x="205" y="938"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The ﬂight of the Carrion-Crow is somewhat laboured, though at times very
rapid, its wings regularly beating the air; when approaching the earth it usually
wheels round in circles. On the earth it either walks, or, if in a hurry, leaps
forward with half opened wings after the fashion of its kind.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="206" y="939"/>
	<Point x="2103" y="935"/>
	<Point x="2104" y="2061"/>
	<Point x="213" y="2063"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The time of nidiﬁcation of the Carrion-Crow is from the latter half of April
to nearly the end of May (a clutch which I purchased from a shepherd, whose
boys had just taken them from a nest near the top of an elm-tree at Iwade near
Sheppy, consisted of three full-sized eggs and one small yolkless one, all of which
were quite fresh on May 25th). The nest is bulky and the same structure is
believed to be used and added to year after year; it is either placed in a niche,
or on a ledge of rock, or in a tall tree,—oak, elm, or pine; but in Holland it is
said to be built upon the ground. J. B. Pilley, of Hereford (“Zoologist,” 1891,
p. 352), records the discovery of a nest containing ﬁve eggs on the top of a tall
hedge, in some meadows near the city. The nest is somewhat ﬂat and formed of
dead sticks, twigs, grass-tussocks and roots, with a lining of fur, wool, feathers
or other soft materials neatly smoothed down. The eggs number from four to
six, ﬁve being a frequent clutch, and are sometimes indistinguishable from those
of the Raven, but usually they are somewhat smaller; the ground-colour is bluish-
green and the markings which vary considerably in density consist of spots,
longitudinal streaks and blotches of olive and olive-brown; some of the markings
are frequently almost black and others almost grey. It is believed that this Crow
pairs for life.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="212" y="2064"/>
	<Point x="1873" y="2063"/>
	<Point x="2104" y="2064"/>
	<Point x="2103" y="2247"/>
	<Point x="212" y="2251"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Of the eggs of this species ﬁgured on our plate, ﬁgs. 233, 234 and 235 are
from Mr. Farn’s collection, and 236 from that of Mr. Frohawk’s; my own
specimens were not varied or characteristic enough to be worth representing.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="212" y="2252"/>
	<Point x="2106" y="2248"/>
	<Point x="2105" y="2744"/>
	<Point x="212" y="2752"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The call is a hoarse croak, but some of the other cries of this species are
less objectionable. The food of this bird in summer consists of almost any kind
of animal too weak or sickly to defend itself, wounded sheep, helpless lambs, the
young of hares and rabbits, moles, young poultry, ducks, pheasants, partridges,
and grouse; but he does not conﬁne himself entirely to this diet, he also feeds
on mollusca, which he extracts from the shells (as mentioned many years ago by
Messrs. Sheppard and Whitear) by carrying them up to a considerable height
and dropping them on to a stone; stale ﬁsh cast up by the waves, and carrion</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="320" y="2764"/>
	<Point x="320" y="2810"/>
	<Point x="446" y="2810"/>
	<Point x="446" y="2764"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>VOL. II.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="signature-mark">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1736" y="2752"/>
	<Point x="1736" y="2800"/>
	<Point x="1823" y="2800"/>
	<Point x="1823" y="2752"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Y2</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
