<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00668263">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-11T20:20:45</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T09:52:48</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00668263.tif" imageWidth="2526" imageHeight="3172">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r1" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="6"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="7"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="8"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r10" index="9"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1088" y="277"/>
	<Point x="1477" y="277"/>
	<Point x="1477" y="344"/>
	<Point x="1088" y="344"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>BULIMUS.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1209" y="379"/>
	<Point x="1359" y="379"/>
	<Point x="1359" y="425"/>
	<Point x="1209" y="425"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>PLATE I.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="592" y="462"/>
	<Point x="1051" y="462"/>
	<Point x="1051" y="514"/>
	<Point x="592" y="514"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Genus BULIMUS, Lamarck.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="375" y="529"/>
	<Point x="1268" y="529"/>
	<Point x="1268" y="870"/>
	<Point x="375" y="870"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Testa ovata, vel oblonga, vel turrita, anfractibus nunc per-
paucis, ventricosis, nunc plurimis, contractis, aut fra-
gilibus et sæpè translucidis, aut crassiusculis, epidermide
interdum duplici indutis; columellâ rectâ, interdum uni-
plicatâ, basi nunquam truncatâ; aperturâ nonnunquam
dentatâ, plerumque integrâ, marginibus disjunctis, labro
vel simplici, vel reﬂexo. Operculum nullum.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="371" y="872"/>
	<Point x="1263" y="872"/>
	<Point x="1264" y="1255"/>
	<Point x="370" y="1255"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Shell ovate, oblong, or turreted, whorls sometimes very
few and ventricose, sometimes many and contracted,
either fragile and often transparent, or rather thick,
covered with, sometimes, a double diaphanous epi-
dermis; columella straight, sometimes one-plaited,
never truncated at the base; aperture in some in-
stances toothed, generally entire, with the margins
disjoined, lip either simple or reﬂected.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="350" y="1274"/>
	<Point x="1261" y="1274"/>
	<Point x="1261" y="2668"/>
	<Point x="350" y="2668"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The beautiful forms and varieties of shells produced by
those air-breathing mollusks, which, under the generic
appellation of Bulimus, constitute an important division
of the great tribe of SNAILS, have become objects of
especial interest to the conchologist, owing to the zeal
with which a few enterprising scientiﬁc travellers have
lately penetrated into tropical countries in pursuit of them.
It is, however, to the productive exertions of Mr. Cuming
that we are mainly indebted for the newer and more
attractive subjects of the present monograph. The re-
searches of this ardent naturalist in the arid plains on the
west side of the Andes, in the dense woods of West
Columbia and Central America, and, more recently, in
the luxuriant open forests of the Philippine Islands, whilst
they present an instructive contrast, exceed any result
the most sanguine collector could have anticipated. In
the dry and barren regions of Western Chili and Peru,
the Bulimi are mostly small and of comparatively fragile
structure; but in the beautiful islands of the Eastern
Archipelago, where climate and vegetation combine to
favour the growth of arboreal species, the genus is
represented with proliﬁc splendour. Mr. Cuming must
have truly felt like one transported to the fabled garden of
the Hesperides, when beholding the lofty trees of these
sunny isles laden with snails of such magniﬁcent propor-
tions. Aladdin, in the Arabian tale, could not, surely,
have contemplated the rich clusters of vari-coloured fruit
in the garden of the African Magician with more astonish-
ment, nor probably gathered it with more avidity.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1296" y="464"/>
	<Point x="2187" y="464"/>
	<Point x="2187" y="1468"/>
	<Point x="1299" y="1469"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“It was in 1836,” relates Mr. Broderip, “that Mr.
Cuming proceeded to the Philippine Islands by permission
of the Queen Regent of Spain, and aided by powerful
recommendations from her government, which opened to
him the interior of the islands, and caused him to be
received with a noble hospitality, equalled only by the
warm interest which facilitated his pursuits wherever he
arrived and made himself known.” Species of which we
had but an imperfect knowledge, in consequence of the
bad condition in which a stray individual chanced to
reach our cabinets, were found in luxuriant plenty, and
many new kinds were discovered in their airy solitude in
equal abundance. Had De Férussac, the enthusiastic
admirer of this tribe, lived to see the glorious series of
Bulimi accumulated in the Cumingian collection in diﬀerent
stages of growth, and in the ﬁnest state of preservation,
from the egg to the adult, he would have been indeed
amazed. Sorry am I that the limits of the present work
will not allow me to illustrate more than two, or occa-
sionally three, of the typical varieties of each species, and
of these but a single view.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1296" y="1472"/>
	<Point x="2183" y="1472"/>
	<Point x="2183" y="2131"/>
	<Point x="1320" y="2131"/>
	<Point x="1317" y="2136"/>
	<Point x="1296" y="2136"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The genus Bulimus, as restricted by Lamarck, compre-
hends an extremely natural group, though presenting
important diﬀerences of growth and texture; and these
variations are peculiarly local. In the Philippine Islands,
as just described, the species are of large and rather solid
growth with a remarkable hydrophanous epidermis, that
is, one permeable by water or other evaporable ﬂuid.
On the barren hills of Lima and the sandy plains of Chili
and Peru, they are mostly small and delicately formed;
in Brazil, the species are remarkable for having the aper-
ture in frequent instances denticulated; and in New
Caledonia, Venezuela, New Grenada, and New Hebrides,
they not uncommonly exhibit, with equal peculiarity, a
plaited Auricula-like columella.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1292" y="2139"/>
	<Point x="1329" y="2139"/>
	<Point x="1330" y="2134"/>
	<Point x="2177" y="2134"/>
	<Point x="2175" y="2659"/>
	<Point x="1292" y="2659"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is a curious feature in the Philippine species that
the varieties of pattern, which constitute their chief orna-
ment, reside only in the epidermis. The colours of the
shell rarely describe any sort of conﬁguration: they are
mostly blended into a uniform tint, over which a fanciful
pattern is produced by the epidermis forming a double
porous membrane in some places, and a single one only
in others, developed, moreover, with the same continuous
regularity as the textile marking of a Volute or Cone.
This phenomenon is easily detected by immersing the
shell in water, when the light portion or upper porous</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1175" y="2705"/>
	<Point x="1370" y="2705"/>
	<Point x="1370" y="2753"/>
	<Point x="1175" y="2753"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>April, 1848.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r11">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1273" y="465"/>
	<Point x="1269" y="1719"/>
	<Point x="1267" y="2650"/>
	<Point x="1283" y="2650"/>
	<Point x="1290" y="463"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
