<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672751">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:36:01</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:47</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672751.tif" imageWidth="1912" imageHeight="3226">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="748" y="261"/>
	<Point x="1001" y="261"/>
	<Point x="1001" y="305"/>
	<Point x="748" y="305"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>FRACTURES.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1555" y="250"/>
	<Point x="1656" y="250"/>
	<Point x="1656" y="305"/>
	<Point x="1555" y="305"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>217</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="76" y="359"/>
	<Point x="1662" y="359"/>
	<Point x="1662" y="1209"/>
	<Point x="76" y="1209"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>by the organ of hearing, it can scarcely be called a sound, for the
grating of the parts, as the rubbing takes place, is often more felt
than heard, but there is no mistaking its import in cases favorable
for the application of the test. The conditions in which it is not
available are those of incomplete fracture, in which the mobility
of the parts is lacking; and those in which the whole array of
phenomena are usually obscure. To obtain the beneﬁt of this
pathognomonic sign requires deliberate, careful, and gentle man-
ipulation. Sometimes the slightest movements will be suﬃcient
for its development, after much rougher handling has failed to
discover it. Perhaps the failure in the latter case is due to a sort
of defensive spasmodic rigidity caused by the pain resulting from
the rude interference.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="86" y="1215"/>
	<Point x="1661" y="1215"/>
	<Point x="1661" y="1473"/>
	<Point x="86" y="1473"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>More or less reactive fever is a usual accompaniment of a frac-
ture, and an ecchymosis of the parts is but a natural occurrence,
more easily discovered in animals possessing a light-colored and
delicate skin than in those of the opposite character.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="79" y="1477"/>
	<Point x="1663" y="1477"/>
	<Point x="1663" y="2512"/>
	<Point x="79" y="2512"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>There are diﬃculties in the way of the diagnosis of an incom-
plete fracture, even sometimes when there is a degree of impair-
ment in the function of locomotion, with evidences of pain and
swelling at the seat of lesion. There should then be a careful
examination for the evidences of a blow or other violence suﬃcient
to account for the fracture, though very often a suspicion of its
existence can only be converted into a certainty by a minute his-
tory of the patient if it can be obtained up to the moment of the
occurrence of the injury. A diagnosis ought not to be hastily
pronounced, and where good ground for suspicion exists it ought
not to be rejected upon any evidence less than the best. Serious
and fatal complications are too often recorded of the results fol-
lowing careless conclusions in similar cases, among which we may
refer to one instance of a complete fracture manifesting itself in
an animal during the act of rising up in his stall after a decision
had been pronouuced that he had no fracture at all.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="90" y="2515"/>
	<Point x="1662" y="2515"/>
	<Point x="1662" y="2969"/>
	<Point x="90" y="2969"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Fractures are of course liable to complications, those especial-
ly, from the nature of the case, which are of a traumatic
character, such as extensive lacerations, tearing of tissues, punc-
tures, contusions, etc. But unless these are in communication
with the fracture itself, the indication is to treat them simply
as independent lesions upon the other parts of the body. A
traumatic emphysema will at times cause trouble, and abscesses,</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
