<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672759">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-09T04:06:27</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:47</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672759.tif" imageWidth="1894" imageHeight="3294">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="240" y="192"/>
	<Point x="361" y="192"/>
	<Point x="361" y="264"/>
	<Point x="240" y="264"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>134</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="661" y="202"/>
	<Point x="1307" y="202"/>
	<Point x="1307" y="257"/>
	<Point x="661" y="257"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>TELEGONY AND REVERSION.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="228" y="297"/>
	<Point x="1761" y="297"/>
	<Point x="1761" y="1833"/>
	<Point x="228" y="1833"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>ancestors are due to reversion, either towards the less
remote ancestors of the zebras or horses, or towards the
common ancestors of all the recent Equidæ.* In considering
the question, Were the ancestors of the horse striped?
it has been incidentally shown that all foals do not pass
through a striped stage, and that many foals have stripes
at birth which ordinarily completely or all but completely
disappear. That foals are usually of a bay or dun colour,
and frequently striped at birth, seems to be best accounted
for by saying they wear for a time their ancestral colours,
either owing to the inﬂuence of simple heredity, or to an
extraordinary kind of heredity, commonly known as atavism
or reversion. It has been especially shown that the greater
the diﬀerence between the sire and the dam, the greater
the reversion is likely to be; and, it may be added, the
longer are the ancestral markings likely to be retained.
For example, hybrids between two distinct species usually
resemble the remote ancestors more than crosses between
two varieties or races, and while cross-bred forms (crosses
between closely allied races or varieties) may soon lose any
hints they may have of remote ancestors at birth, hybrids
generally retain the ancestral characters throughout life.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="676" y="1854"/>
	<Point x="1304" y="1854"/>
	<Point x="1304" y="1930"/>
	<Point x="676" y="1930"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Nature of Telegony.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="230" y="1942"/>
	<Point x="1747" y="1942"/>
	<Point x="1747" y="2723"/>
	<Point x="230" y="2723"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Having considered the question, Were the ancestors of
the horse striped? and the still more important question,
Does reversion occur in the Equidæ? we are now in a
position to deal more eﬀectively with the telegony problem,
as far as the horse family is concerned. It will be evident
that by assuming horses have descended from striped
ancestors, and that the less remote ancestors sometimes
still reassert themselves, that by what we term atavism or
reversion horses even now sometimes wear the ancestral
colours, it will be evident that by granting these premises
the question has been enormously complicated.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="230" y="2730"/>
	<Point x="1750" y="2730"/>
	<Point x="1750" y="2928"/>
	<Point x="230" y="2928"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>* Or to use Mr. Galton's phraseology, the hybrids have reverted so as
to resemble the hypothetical “midparent,” uniting the characters of their
respective remote ancestors.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
