<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672716">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:33:02</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672716.tif" imageWidth="2090" imageHeight="3234">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="395" y="169"/>
	<Point x="1876" y="169"/>
	<Point x="1876" y="250"/>
	<Point x="395" y="250"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Bulletin of the Brooklyn Entomological Society Vol. XVIII</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="240" y="335"/>
	<Point x="1866" y="335"/>
	<Point x="1866" y="873"/>
	<Point x="240" y="873"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Fig. 2, are quite like the paraprocts pa of the roach shown in Fig.
1; but the cerci ce of the termite are not as well developed as those
of the roach. Certain termites, such as Architermopsis, however,
have quite large and well-developed cerci. In this connection, I
would call attention to the fact that certain sawﬂies have long
slender cerci quite suggestive of those of Architermopsis, as I
hope to show in a subsequent paper dealing with the anatomy of
the sawﬂies.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="219" y="881"/>
	<Point x="1871" y="880"/>
	<Point x="1871" y="1709"/>
	<Point x="219" y="1709"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the Isoptera and Blattids the epiproct ep (Figs. 1 and 2) is
largely formed by the tenth tergite, and in the Mantids also the
tenth tergite is large (and the eleventh tergite becomes greatly
reduced and is largely concealed by the tenth). I am not sure
that the posterior portion of the plate labeled ep in Fig. 1 is not
the representative of the eleventh tergite, but I have provisionally
interpreted it as a posterior portion of the tenth tergite. The ninth
and eighth tergites labeled 8t and 9t in Fig. 1 are greatly narrowed
in the roach there depicted, but in other roaches they are a little
broader. In the absence of a marked reduction or narrowing of
these tergites in the Isoptera, the latter resemble the Phasmids and
Orthoptera in some respects.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="235" y="1711"/>
	<Point x="1873" y="1711"/>
	<Point x="1873" y="2597"/>
	<Point x="235" y="2597"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Taking the terminal structures in general, Mastotermes resem-
bles the Blattids more than any other insects, and in connection
with other features such as the venation of the wings, the char-
acter of the cervical sclerites, etc., a study of the ovipostor, hy-
pogynum, etc., in Mastotermes, would materially strengthen the
view that the Isoptera are more closely related to the Blattids than
to any other living insects, and likewise indicates that the super-
order Panisoptera (composed of the Blattids, Mantids, Isoptera,
etc.) is a natural one. In some respects, the Dermaptera bear a
marked resemblance to the members of this superorder, but for the
present, at least, I would leave the Dermaptera in the superorder
Panorthoptera (including the Orthoptera, s. str., the Phasmids,
etc.).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="230" y="2602"/>
	<Point x="1869" y="2602"/>
	<Point x="1869" y="2873"/>
	<Point x="230" y="2873"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The study of the structures present in Mastotermes is of prime
importance, since it is one of the most primitive representatives of
the order Isoptera, and the Isoptera are in many respects the
nearest living representatives of the Protorthoptera-like ancestors</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r6">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="223" y="259"/>
	<Point x="1861" y="259"/>
	<Point x="1861" y="285"/>
	<Point x="223" y="285"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="219" y="166"/>
	<Point x="330" y="166"/>
	<Point x="330" y="240"/>
	<Point x="219" y="240"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>88</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
