<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672703">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:31:56</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:44</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672703.tif" imageWidth="1940" imageHeight="3182">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="645" y="190"/>
	<Point x="1295" y="190"/>
	<Point x="1295" y="257"/>
	<Point x="645" y="257"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE ADDER IN SOLWAY</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1666" y="197"/>
	<Point x="1750" y="197"/>
	<Point x="1750" y="261"/>
	<Point x="1666" y="261"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>157</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="169" y="304"/>
	<Point x="1764" y="304"/>
	<Point x="1764" y="578"/>
	<Point x="169" y="578"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>which I was totally unacquainted. The adders are in great
numbers about the banks of the Garpel, and the eels
probably catch them about the edge of the water, but it
seems very remarkable how they get them at all.’”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="169" y="580"/>
	<Point x="1785" y="580"/>
	<Point x="1785" y="1661"/>
	<Point x="169" y="1661"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>In the “Courier” for 10th October 1826 the editor again
reverts to the foregoing letter, stating that his correspondent
was a Mr. Lorimer, and that after dissecting the eel as
related, the ﬁsh had been ﬂung down. “In the course
of the very same week, he (Mr. Lorimer) caught several
more eels, and though these appeared to be sound and
good, the recollection of what had occurred before excited
such a prejudice against them that it was unnecessary to
cook what no one would eat. These, therefore, he also
ﬂung away under a tree beside the former, and on passing
the spot soon after he was surprised to ﬁnd myriads of ﬂies
preying on the eels caught last, and not one attacking the
other. . . . Here, then, we have the testimony of a respect-
able individual to two rather curious facts—ﬁrst, that eels
devour adders; and secondly, that ﬂies have a perception
of, and shun any poisonous substance.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="173" y="1669"/>
	<Point x="1785" y="1669"/>
	<Point x="1785" y="2411"/>
	<Point x="173" y="2411"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Since I ﬁrst read this paragraph I have often watched
a dead adder, and found that ﬂies had no hesitation in
sucking its juices, or laying their eggs upon the carcase.
To be sure, I have not had the chance of experimenting
with an eel that had swallowed an adder. Here is a
paragraph that bears upon the former abundance of the
adder in the Stewartry: “On Friday week Mr. James
Neilson, on the farm of Lochend, about three miles to the
south of the Nine-mile Tollbar, killed at one shot seven
adders, one of which was as long as a man's arm”
(28th August 1832).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="2416"/>
	<Point x="1783" y="2416"/>
	<Point x="1783" y="3033"/>
	<Point x="185" y="3033"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>For nearly thirty years following, the species is not
mentioned in the “Courier” at all. But on 25th September
1860 occurs the following: “Adders are reported as being
unusually plentiful in various portions of Scotland this
season, and sportsmen and others who have been treading
the moors and wilds of Dumfriesshire and Galloway conﬁrm
the statement. As the so-called summer has been wet and
cold, the abundance of adders, which love heat and sunshine,
is rather remarkable. Probably the hot and dry summer of</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
