<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672712">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T17:02:40</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672712.tif" imageWidth="2072" imageHeight="3406">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="226" y="173"/>
	<Point x="357" y="173"/>
	<Point x="357" y="254"/>
	<Point x="226" y="254"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>372</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="816" y="185"/>
	<Point x="1319" y="185"/>
	<Point x="1319" y="252"/>
	<Point x="816" y="252"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>PLEUROTOMIDÆ.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="214" y="309"/>
	<Point x="1923" y="309"/>
	<Point x="1923" y="1514"/>
	<Point x="214" y="1514"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Bay, co. Galway (Walpole); Cork (Humphreys); co.
Antrim, in 60 f. oﬀ Loch Ewe, and in 43 f. on the
Shetland coast (J. G. J.). The variety is from Fal-
mouth (Cocks and Barlee); Shetland, 78-86 f. (Barlee
and J. G. J.). D. reticulata belongs to our Red and
Coralline Crag (S. Wood, as Clavatula cancellata), and
to the Italian tertiaries (Philippi and Calcara). It is
spread along the north-Atlantic coasts, from Brittany
(Collard des Cherres and Taslé) to Gibraltar (M‘An-
drew), and throughout the Mediterranean, Adriatic,
and Ægean, at depths of from 4 to 35 f. The variety
has been dredged by Lilljeborg in Norway, by Lovén
and Malm in Bohuslän (by the latter in 40 f.), and by
Forbes in the Ægean (as var. spinosa) in 105 f.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="228" y="1521"/>
	<Point x="1930" y="1521"/>
	<Point x="1930" y="2452"/>
	<Point x="228" y="2452"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>This species varies remarkably in size. An Irish
adult specimen is only three lines long; another, from
Shetland (the varietal form), measures nearly an inch
and a quarter. Those from the Mediterranean are of
two kinds, one like ours, and the other (which is more
usual) having a shorter spire and very tumid whorls,
and averaging three-quarters of an inch in length. The
latter may therefore be considered the typical form.
The variety is extremely beautiful, and almost “para-
gons description;” it will be ﬁgured in the next
volume.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="228" y="2464"/>
	<Point x="1928" y="2464"/>
	<Point x="1928" y="3247"/>
	<Point x="228" y="3247"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is the Murex cancellatus of J. Sowerby (not Pleu-
rotoma cancellata of Calcara, nor Fusus cancellatus of
Mighels and Adams, both of which appear to be also
species of Defrancia), M. echinatus of Brocchi, Pleuro-
toma Cordieri of Payraudeau, P. rude of Scacchi, and
P. purpureum of Philippi—not M. purpureus of Mon-
tagu; I described the present species as P. scabrum,
under the impression that it was distinct from the
Mediterranean shell and not merely a variety.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
