<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672709">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:32:24</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672709.tif" imageWidth="2254" imageHeight="3788">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="187" y="395"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="395"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="1577"/>
	<Point x="187" y="1577"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>must ascribe the enormous quantities of game-birds that are
annually consumed by people who never saw one alive. At
his call skilled huntsmen took the ﬁeld, employing every means
ingenuity could suggest to increase the catch. Nets, snares,
traps, decoys, and ponderous guns were in constant use. For
years professional hunters slaughtered, dealers handled, and
gluttons gobbled without reason or restraint. There could be
but one result: wild fowl have become scarce. Gunners no
longer return at night with more birds than they can carry;
not seldom they come in empty-handed. But the millionaire
makes up the shortage by paying higher prices. When a pair
of canvas-backs bring a ﬁve-dollar note there is still money in
shooting ducks.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="1581"/>
	<Point x="2144" y="1581"/>
	<Point x="2144" y="3577"/>
	<Point x="185" y="3577"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The same lavish fancy that prompts a rich gourmand to buy
high-priced ducks prompts him to spend an equal sum for a
box of strawberries out of season. The ducks are actually
not ﬁner than others of less repute; the berries are not sweeter
nor better-ﬂavored than those he buys in spring at ten cents a
box. His purchases are made without regard either to cost or
intrinsic worth. He has reached a point where gratiﬁcation
outweighs money. But let us see the diﬀerence to us whether
he spends it for berries or for ducks. When he buys berries
he pays the gardener a special price for a special kind of skill
and for maintaining an expensive establishment a fair recom-
pense. The fruit is as truly the sole property of the horti-
culturist as is the money the sole property of the purchaser.
The transaction is legitimate. Now as to ducks. The gunner
receives pay for skill and toil, as in the other case; but the
birds are his only by an acquisition not wholly above question.
He has spent nothing on their nurture. He disposes of what
we have as clear a title to as he if we would but make it good
by scouring the marshes. Such a title may not be very strong,
but it has a certain validity nevertheless. As a democratic
people, there is but one light in which we can regard game,—
that is, as public property. If there were an inexhaustible</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="263"/>
	<Point x="340" y="263"/>
	<Point x="340" y="336"/>
	<Point x="185" y="336"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>274</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r11" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="522" y="259"/>
	<Point x="1787" y="259"/>
	<Point x="1787" y="342"/>
	<Point x="522" y="342"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>BIRDS IN THEIR RELATIONS TO MAN.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
