<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672715">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:32:55</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:45</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672715.tif" imageWidth="1691" imageHeight="2328">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="6"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="7"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="151" y="113"/>
	<Point x="1591" y="113"/>
	<Point x="1591" y="514"/>
	<Point x="151" y="514"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>base in the species respectively) but are anatomically members of the group. A
seventh species, B. loveridgii, may belong to the B. kerstenii group but it is excluded
here because of its short barbels and slightly higher range of lateral-line scale counts.
The latter character is, however, paralleled within the group by B. neumayeri. Rela-
tively short barbels would also seem to exclude B. nyanzae Whitehead, a species
known only from aﬄuent rivers in the Lake Victoria basin. But in this case the
diﬀerence is less trenchant and the species is therefore included. When a more
comprehensive deﬁnition of B. loveridgii is available it too may have to be added to
the B. kerstenii group.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="159" y="517"/>
	<Point x="1591" y="517"/>
	<Point x="1591" y="910"/>
	<Point x="159" y="910"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Barbus kerstenii appears to be polytypic, with at least one well-deﬁned subspecies in
Lake Luhondo (see p. 172) and possibly two others representing the northern and
southern populations of its range in East Africa. The ranges of B. neumayeri,
B. pellegrini and B. kerstenii overlap in several regions (Kenya, Uganda, and in Lake
Tanganyika) but that of B. eutaenia is distinct except for ﬁshes in Ruanda Urundi
(see p. 176). Barbus tangandensis also has a distinct range (Rhodesia), but the species
may be considered as the regional representative of the B. kerstenii stock (see p. 175).
Within its restricted range, the distribution of B. nyanzae overlaps that of B. neumayeri
and B. kerstenii.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="148" y="913"/>
	<Point x="1597" y="913"/>
	<Point x="1597" y="1267"/>
	<Point x="148" y="1267"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The third group (scales small to moderate [lateral line with 28-30 scales] dorsal
and pelvic ﬁn origins in the same perpendicular line, last unbranched dorsal ray
spinous and serrated, snout strongly decurved, broad preorbital face and barbels
well-developed) comprises two rather poorly known species, Barbus sexradiatus
(endemic to Lake Victoria) and B. laticeps (only recorded from the Wami River
system of Tanganyika). The broad head and strongly decurved snout are the most
obvious characteristics of the group. Until more specimens are available, particularly
of B. sexradiatus, little more can be said.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="155" y="1271"/>
	<Point x="1598" y="1271"/>
	<Point x="1598" y="1624"/>
	<Point x="156" y="1625"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The fourth and last group also comprises two species, Barbus trimaculatus and
B. jacksonii; it is characterized by small scales (30–39 in the lateral line, modal
ranges for the species 32–33 and 37–38 respectively), enlarged, spinous but non-
serrate last unbranched dorsal ray, and well-developed barbels. In addition, both
species have three distinct midlateral spots on the ﬂanks, but this is not necessarily
to be considered a group character. There is a clear gap in the distribution of these
species, and each could be considered the geographical representative of the other
(see p. 185).</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="150" y="1628"/>
	<Point x="1597" y="1627"/>
	<Point x="1597" y="1755"/>
	<Point x="150" y="1755"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>There remain three species, B. zanzibaricus, B. magdalenae and B. apleurogramma
which cannot be placed in any group within the broad geographical region of East,
Central, and southern Africa.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="154" y="1758"/>
	<Point x="1601" y="1758"/>
	<Point x="1601" y="1935"/>
	<Point x="154" y="1935"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Barbus zanzibaricus, a species of relatively restricted distribution, shows certain
aﬃnities with the B. kerstenii group, but is perhaps more closely allied to B. argenteus
of Angola. Its group relationship must await further analysis, particularly of the West
African species.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="154" y="1937"/>
	<Point x="1604" y="1937"/>
	<Point x="1604" y="2066"/>
	<Point x="154" y="2066"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Barbus magdalenae, a Lake Victoria endemic, is unlikely to be grouped with any
described species of eastern or western Africa; consequently its phyletic relationships
also remain obscure.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="191" y="2068"/>
	<Point x="1594" y="2068"/>
	<Point x="1594" y="2120"/>
	<Point x="191" y="2120"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The third species, B. apleurogramma, diﬀers from the other two in having a much</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r11" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="154" y="52"/>
	<Point x="222" y="52"/>
	<Point x="222" y="95"/>
	<Point x="154" y="95"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>204</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r17" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="251" y="50"/>
	<Point x="1498" y="50"/>
	<Point x="1498" y="90"/>
	<Point x="251" y="90"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>A REVISION OF CERTAIN BARBUS SPECIES FROM AFRICA</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
