<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672706">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:32:02</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:44</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672706.tif" imageWidth="1961" imageHeight="3024">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="196" y="166"/>
	<Point x="287" y="166"/>
	<Point x="287" y="244"/>
	<Point x="196" y="244"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>78</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="823" y="158"/>
	<Point x="1183" y="158"/>
	<Point x="1183" y="221"/>
	<Point x="823" y="221"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE APPLE</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="185" y="278"/>
	<Point x="1821" y="278"/>
	<Point x="1821" y="1157"/>
	<Point x="185" y="1157"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>be squeezed round with index ﬁnger and thumb, and then inserted
carefully into the detonator, well down to the explosive charge.
Do not twist it about. The charge is very sensitive and friction
may explode it. Although this operation is not dangerous, yet
great care should be exercised. After the fuse is inserted into
the detonator as above described, take the cap crimper and crimp
the detonator to the fuse. The crimp should be made near the end
which the fuse enters, so as not to disturb in any way the explo-
sive charge which the blasting cap contains. Do not use common
pincers, knife, or the teeth in this operation. If the work is wet,
then smear the joint with tallow, wax, or soap. Do not use oily
grease, as the oil might penetrate the fuse wrapping and spoil
the powder.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="196" y="1160"/>
	<Point x="1824" y="1160"/>
	<Point x="1824" y="1558"/>
	<Point x="196" y="1558"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The next step. The next operation is the insertion of the cap
into the dynamite cartridge. This may be done by punching a
hole diagonally into the side of the cartridge, inserting the blast-
ing cap into it, and tying the fuse to the side of the cartridge with
a piece of twine. Electric fusees may be inserted and fastened in
the same manner.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="194" y="1564"/>
	<Point x="1821" y="1564"/>
	<Point x="1821" y="2874"/>
	<Point x="194" y="2874"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Having primed the cartridge in the manner described, insert it
in the borehole on top, or next to the top of the rest of the charge
if more than one cartridge is used, and push it carefully home.
Putting the explosive into the borehole is called charging or load-
ing the borehole. It is generally best in dry ground to slit the
paper shells lengthwise in two or three places with a sharp knife
before putting the cartridge into the borehole, as a slit cartridge
will spread out in the borehole better. The primer should not be
slit. Push the cartridges, except the primer cartridge, ﬁrmly into
place with a wooden stick so that they will expand and ﬁll up their
part of the hole, for crevices or air spaces may lessen the power
of the explosive. Expanded cartridges also occupy less of the
length of the borehole and make possible a heavy charge at the
bottom of the hole. The primer is loaded last, or next to the last,
and is pushed down only hard enough to touch the preceding
cartridge. Each cartridge must touch the one previously loaded,
for if there is any space between the cartridge caused by falling
dirt or stones, or by the sticking of a cartridge in the borehole,
a part of the charge may fail to explode.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
