<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672773">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-09T04:07:34</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:47</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672773.tif" imageWidth="1813" imageHeight="3142">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="236" y="200"/>
	<Point x="336" y="200"/>
	<Point x="336" y="260"/>
	<Point x="236" y="260"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>122</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="657" y="213"/>
	<Point x="1215" y="213"/>
	<Point x="1215" y="257"/>
	<Point x="657" y="257"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>LANDSCAPE GARDENING.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="210" y="326"/>
	<Point x="1647" y="326"/>
	<Point x="1647" y="1190"/>
	<Point x="210" y="1190"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>age and immense size, which attests the ﬁtness of the soil
and climate, and displays the grandeur of our native species
The Wadsworth Oak near Geneseo, N. Y., of extraordinary
dimensions, the product of one of our most fertile valleys,
has attracted the admiration of hundreds of travellers on
the route to Niagara. Its trunk measures thirty-six feet in
circumference. The celebrated Charter Oak at Hartford,
which has ﬁgured so conspicuously in the history of New
England, is still existing in a green old age, one of the most
interesting monuments of the past to be found in the
country.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="219" y="1206"/>
	<Point x="1636" y="1206"/>
	<Point x="1636" y="1839"/>
	<Point x="219" y="1839"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Near the village of Flushing, Long Island, on the farm
of Judge Lawrence, is growing one of the noblest oaks in
the country. It is truly park-like in its dimensions, the
circumference of the trunk being nearly thirty feet, and its
majestic head of corresponding dignity. In the deep
alluvial soil of the western valleys, the oak often assumes
a grand aspect, and bears witness to the wonderful fertility
of the soil in that region.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="225" y="1988"/>
	<Point x="1637" y="1988"/>
	<Point x="1637" y="2786"/>
	<Point x="225" y="2786"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Diﬀerent species of Oak. This country is peculiarly
rich in various kinds of oak; Michaux enumerating no less
than forty species indigenous to North America. Of these
the most useful are the Live oak (Quercus virens), of such
inestimable value for ship-building ; the Spanish oak (Q.
falcata); the Red oak (Q. rubra), etc., the bark of which
is extensively used in tanning; the Quercitron or Black
oak, which is highly valuable as aﬀording a ﬁne yellow or
brown dye for wool, silks, paper-hangings, etc. ; and the
White oak, which is chieﬂy used for timber. We shall</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
