<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672780">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:38:07</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:48</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672780.tif" imageWidth="2358" imageHeight="3666">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r1" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="692" y="773"/>
	<Point x="1607" y="773"/>
	<Point x="1607" y="865"/>
	<Point x="692" y="865"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>CHAPTER XI.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="522" y="924"/>
	<Point x="1768" y="924"/>
	<Point x="1768" y="1000"/>
	<Point x="522" y="1000"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>THE IVY FOR DECORATIVE PURPOSES.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="119" y="1028"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="1028"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="1513"/>
	<Point x="119" y="1513"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The Ivy might be called the poor man's vine, for, like the Wilson Strawberry,
it will grow for almost every one. It is the easiest of all the vines for indoor
use, both in growing and for training, and not a little of its merits as a favorite
window plant are its permanency, for it will live long in one pot without change
of soil or position. It accommodates itself to all temperatures save that below
freezing, and when in full growth it adds more grace to the window than any
plant yet used.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="116" y="1519"/>
	<Point x="2173" y="1519"/>
	<Point x="2173" y="1722"/>
	<Point x="116" y="1722"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The English Ivy (IIedera helix) is what is styled a rooted climber, as from
every little joint roots will spring out and take hold of any support. This is
one great advantage of value over other climbing vines which must be trained.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="114" y="1726"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="1726"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="2619"/>
	<Point x="114" y="2619"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is hardly adapted to our severe wintry climate, and will not live out of
doors unless covered with straw. This renders its use for windows a necessity,
and who that has ever gazed upon its glossy green leaves, drooping with long
garlands of graceful verdure, but has felt it well deserved to be named the most
beautiful of all drawing-room plant decorations. A writer speaks of the aﬀec-
tion with which it is esteemed in German houses: " It becomes as one of the
family. Sometimes the whole side of a parlor is covered with it, and twining
around over picture frames, or looped about brackets, drooped over statuettes,
the portraits of father, mother, and cherished friend, look forth smiling from
the leafy environment. Small articles of vertu gleam here and there, touched
with it, framed about mirrors or doors, each heart-shaped dark evergreen leaf,
instinct with loveliness, adds to them all increased beauty. Wherever it goes it
makes a green, perpetual summer of indoor life."</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="116" y="2623"/>
	<Point x="2173" y="2623"/>
	<Point x="2173" y="3160"/>
	<Point x="116" y="3160"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Another writer, viewing it in a poetic view, says: "A single root has been
known to wreathe a bow window with thick garlands, and then strike oﬀ into
lovely, independent paths along picture cords and above cornices, till the room
seemed all a-bud, like Aaron's rod. It will cover a screen of wire, curtain a
curtainless window, festoon a pillar, frame a favorite picture, (and what more
graceful or delicate frame could be desired ?) arch a door, climb and twist about
a window-sill, and swing in long-looped tendrils from a bracket. There is no
end to its beautiful uses.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="115" y="3165"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="3165"/>
	<Point x="2176" y="3446"/>
	<Point x="115" y="3446"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>" Tickle it with a little guano, and how it frolics. Nip oﬀ the terminal shoots,
and lo, two bright, persistent tendrils shoot forth, and curl and twine about your
very ﬁngers. Wash its dusty leaves, and no child could look more gratefully in
your face. It harbors no vermin, encourages no blight, but steadily and sweetly</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
