<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672699">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T06:01:42</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:44</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672699.tif" imageWidth="2158" imageHeight="3522">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="292" y="185"/>
	<Point x="351" y="185"/>
	<Point x="351" y="248"/>
	<Point x="292" y="248"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>ii</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="751" y="187"/>
	<Point x="1596" y="187"/>
	<Point x="1596" y="244"/>
	<Point x="751" y="244"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>BIBLIOGRAPHICAL PREFACE.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="288" y="307"/>
	<Point x="2053" y="307"/>
	<Point x="2053" y="1331"/>
	<Point x="288" y="1331"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>won, and a quiet chat enjoyed with the Master and his
Scholar under a wide tree shedding oﬀ the rain; or by
the ﬁre of the wayside Inn, while the hostess, “clean,
handsome, and civil,” is taking out “sheets smelling of
lavender,” for our beds, in a room that has “more than
twenty ballads stuck against the wall;” or within the little
shrine, Sacrum Piscatoribus, built by Cotton for his father,
and “all true men who love quiet and go an angling.” I
trust that I have drunk enough of the old angler's spirit
not to let such pastime break in upon better things; but,
on the other hand, I have worked the harder from thank-
fulness to HIM who taught the brook to wind with musical
gurglings, as it rolls on to the Great Sea.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="301" y="1335"/>
	<Point x="2059" y="1333"/>
	<Point x="2056" y="3139"/>
	<Point x="301" y="3139"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It has been my wont at such times, to note down what I
happened to ﬁnd, giving greater zest to father Walton's
quaint homilies, not in any hope that others would think it
worth while to share my gatherings, but rather for my
better memory and coming delight. The good publishers
of this darling book, hearing of my little store, have asked
me to put it at their disposal for your use, kind reader; and,
as I count (with honest Shirley in his Angler's Magazine)
“that a person has a mean soul, that could die without
disclosing anything he knows, that he might beneﬁt or
please his fellow-creatures,” I have done as they wished.
The whole work has been gone over; the several editions
collated, some notes chosen from the various editors, and, as
you will see, more added by myself. Of how much worth
these last are, you shall judge; but you can never know
what happy hours I have spent in preparing them, or how
truly I wish they may be to your liking. A good and
pious friend of mine (how good and pious I dare not say,
for he will surely read what I write, and I would spare
him a blush even at his own true praise) has told me that it
was reading this book, which awakened the love of God
in his heart; nor may we wonder, that such meek-hearted,
cheerful strains of godly contentment should have been</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<SeparatorRegion id="r5">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="307" y="266"/>
	<Point x="2051" y="266"/>
	<Point x="2051" y="294"/>
	<Point x="307" y="294"/></Coords></SeparatorRegion></Page></PcGts>
