<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672779">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T17:08:00</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:48</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672779.tif" imageWidth="2059" imageHeight="3296">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r2" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r13" index="1"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="255" y="415"/>
	<Point x="1788" y="415"/>
	<Point x="1788" y="627"/>
	<Point x="255" y="627"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Also another Brewer edition, practically the same as (m), but
with the impring T. L. Magagnos &amp; Company, New York, 1854, 16
Beekman St., as publishers. It also contains a few plates not from
Wilson.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1716" y="286"/>
	<Point x="1788" y="286"/>
	<Point x="1788" y="334"/>
	<Point x="1716" y="334"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>93</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="648" y="282"/>
	<Point x="1409" y="282"/>
	<Point x="1409" y="331"/>
	<Point x="648" y="331"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>BURNS—ALEXANDER WILSON.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r13" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="252" y="653"/>
	<Point x="1790" y="653"/>
	<Point x="1790" y="2838"/>
	<Point x="252" y="2838"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>I have recently had the very great pleasure of examining
valuable manuscript relating to Wilson, collected by the late
Joseph M. Wade, and now in the hands of Mr. Frederic B.
McKechine, who, while reserving the bulk for future publica-
tion, has kindly permitted me to quote certain portions of the
Hazard and Lawson letters. It enables me to conﬁrm the ex-
istence of a Philadelphia edition of Brewer's Wilson, 1856, by
quoting the publisher: " My connection with Wilson was this:
As a publisher in Philadelphia, Harrison Hall who had form-
erly been the publisher of Wilson in 3 Vols. 8vo of text and 1
Vol. 4vo of plates [1828-1829[, who succeeded Laval and
Bradford, the former publishers [Vol. IX of the 1824-25 re-
print]. He used frequently to be in my store on Chestnut
St. between 7th and 8th Sts., and being a very old man, and
desiring of selling the plates, induced me to buy the coppers,
which were all he had of the work, except a number of odd
printed impressions, plain and colored, and a few copies of the
edition of Wilson and Bonaparte in 1 Vol. 8vo edited by Brew-
er of Boston, and which was out of print. I used to buy all
the copies of this letter press I could pick up, and print oﬀ
some plates and color them and thus sell the work. When I
went out of business, I sold the plates to Porter and Coates."1
The latter publishing house made use of them in their 1871
edition, when Mr. Hazard was manager for the ﬁrm and
doubtless superintended this work, and the late Henry T.
Coates informed me that he in turn transferred the plates to
The John C. Winston Co., successors to Henry T. Coates and
Company; therefore I believe the original coppers are still in-
tact after serving ﬁve editions. Mr. Hazard does not state
that the title page of the letter press was replaced by one of
his own, but I regard this as extremely probable, as well as
his own or a close friend's authorship of the notice in Alli-</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r15" type="footnote">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="749" y="2856"/>
	<Point x="1293" y="2856"/>
	<Point x="1293" y="2928"/>
	<Point x="749" y="2928"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>1 Willis P. Hazard MS.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
