<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672768">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T17:07:06</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:47</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672768.tif" imageWidth="2180" imageHeight="3454">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r11" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r14" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r12" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r10" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="5"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="640" y="87"/>
	<Point x="1600" y="87"/>
	<Point x="1600" y="166"/>
	<Point x="640" y="166"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>GALEN: THE MAN AND HIS TIMES</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="1891" y="95"/>
	<Point x="1967" y="95"/>
	<Point x="1967" y="154"/>
	<Point x="1891" y="154"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>83</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="778" y="676"/>
	<Point x="1480" y="676"/>
	<Point x="1480" y="725"/>
	<Point x="778" y="725"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>WESTERN RESERVE UNIVERSITY</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="314" y="2425"/>
	<Point x="1988" y="2425"/>
	<Point x="1988" y="3236"/>
	<Point x="314" y="3236"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>Yet Galen deserves to be remembered, not merely as one of the great
names, but as one of most original minds and attractive personalities
in all the long history of medicine. It is not diﬃcult to make out the
the main events of his life, his works supply an unusual amount of per-
sonal information, and throughout them, unless he is merely transcrib-
ing past prescriptions, he talks like a living man, detailing incidents
of daily life and making upon the reader a vivid and unaﬀected im-
pression of reality. Daremberg said of Galen that the exuberance of
his imagination and his vanity frequently make us smile. It is true
that his pharmacology and therapeutics often strike the modern reader
as ridiculous, but he did not imagine them; they were the medicine of
his age. It is true that he mentions cases which he has cured and those</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r10" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="385" y="928"/>
	<Point x="383" y="823"/>
	<Point x="384" y="810"/>
	<Point x="388" y="799"/>
	<Point x="1981" y="799"/>
	<Point x="1981" y="2423"/>
	<Point x="305" y="2424"/>
	<Point x="294" y="928"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>OR about fifteen centuries the name of Galen dominated the study
of medicine. But at the close of the nineteenth century an Eng-
lish student of the history of medicine said, "Galen is so inaccessible
to English readers that it is diﬃcult to learn about him at ﬁrst hand."
Another wrote, "There is, perhaps, no other instance of a man of equal
intellectual rank who has been so persistently misunderstood and even
misinterpreted." A third obstacle has been that while critical editions
of some single works have recently been published by Helmreich and
others, no complete edition even of the Greek text of Galen has ap-
peared since that of Kühn of a century ago, which is now regarded as
very faulty. A fourth reason for neglect or misunderstanding of Galen
is probably that there is so much by him to be read. Athenaeus stated
that Galen wrote more treatises than any other Greek, and although
many are now lost, more particularly of his logical and philosophical
writings, his collected extant works ﬁll some twenty volumes averaging
a thousand pages each. There are often no chapter headings or other
brief clues to the contents, which must be ploughed through slowly and
thoroughly, since some of the most valuable bits of information come
in quite incidentally or by way of unexpected digression. Besides
errors in the printed text there are numerous words not found in most
classical dictionaries. It is therefore perhaps not surprising, in the
words of one of the English historians of medicine quoted above, that
"few physicians or even scholars in the present day can claim to have
read through this vast collection."</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r12" type="drop-capital">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="294" y="808"/>
	<Point x="380" y="807"/>
	<Point x="382" y="832"/>
	<Point x="380" y="921"/>
	<Point x="294" y="923"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>F</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r11" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="533" y="470"/>
	<Point x="1706" y="470"/>
	<Point x="1706" y="567"/>
	<Point x="533" y="567"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>GALEN: THE MAN AND HIS TIMES</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r14" type="heading">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="534" y="583"/>
	<Point x="1703" y="583"/>
	<Point x="1703" y="662"/>
	<Point x="534" y="662"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>By Professor LYNN THORNDIKE</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
