<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<PcGts xmlns="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19 http://schema.primaresearch.org/PAGE/gts/pagecontent/2010-03-19/pagecontent.xsd" pcGtsId="pc-00672743">
	<Metadata>
	<Creator>ABBYY FineReader Engine 9.0</Creator>
	<Created>2011-08-08T22:35:26</Created>
	<LastChange>2012-02-10T10:29:46</LastChange></Metadata>
	<Page imageFilename="00672743.tif" imageWidth="2398" imageHeight="3791">
	<ReadingOrder>
	<OrderedGroup id="ro357564684568544579089">
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r3" index="0"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r4" index="1"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r5" index="2"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r6" index="3"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r7" index="4"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r8" index="5"/>
	<RegionRefIndexed regionRef="r9" index="6"/></OrderedGroup></ReadingOrder>
	<TextRegion id="r1" type="header">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="316" y="277"/>
	<Point x="1870" y="277"/>
	<Point x="1870" y="338"/>
	<Point x="316" y="338"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>CLASS I. MAMMALIA: ORDER 6. PINNIPEDIA.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r2" type="page-number">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="2040" y="285"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="285"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="340"/>
	<Point x="2040" y="340"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>325</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r3" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="38" y="385"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="385"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="572"/>
	<Point x="38" y="572"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>a man's share besides. A hired master has no share, but usually receives 4d. or 6d. per seal on
the whole cargo. A few of the earliest discharged go out on a second trip, but this is rarely very
productive, as, by the middle of May, all must be home to prepare for the cod-ﬁshery.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r4" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="42" y="577"/>
	<Point x="2159" y="577"/>
	<Point x="2159" y="1787"/>
	<Point x="42" y="1787"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>The seal appears, from many authorities, to possess much intelligence, combined with docility,
gentleness, and aﬀection. F. Cuvier gives some touching details of the manners of a Marbled
Seal—P. discolor—which was living in the menagerie of the Garden of Plants. He says:
“Except in some monkeys, I have never known any wild animal which was more easily tamed,
or attached itself more strongly. When it ﬁrst came to us, it endeavored to escape when I
wished to touch it; but in a very few days all its apprehensions vanished; it had discovered
my intentions, and rather desired my caresses than feared them. It was in the same inclosure
with two small dogs, which amused themselves by frequently mounting on its back, often bark-
ing, and even biting it; and, although these sports, and the vivacity of the attending move-
ments, were little in harmony with its own actions and habits, yet it appreciated their motive,
and seemed pleased with them. It never oﬀered any other retaliation than slight blows with its
paws, the object of which was to encourage rather than repress the liberties taken. If the
puppies escaped from the inclosure, the seal endeavored to follow them. When the weather
was cold, the three animals huddled closely and kindly together. It manifested no fear of man,
nor attempted to avoid him, except to escape the being accidentally trodden upon. It would
also suﬀer, without anger or resistance, the food which it was devouring to be forcibly taken
away, even when hungry; and that not only by man, but also by his canine playfellows. On
the other hand, when their mess was supplied to the seals—for he had a companion—as they
lay in the same trough, a battle was the usual result, and blows with their paws followed, and,
as usually happens, the more feeble and timid left the ﬁeld to the stronger.”</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r5" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="46" y="1791"/>
	<Point x="2167" y="1791"/>
	<Point x="2167" y="2031"/>
	<Point x="46" y="2031"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>It is well known that the seal may be tamed, and in this state shows a remarkable degree of
sagacity. It may be taught to perform various tricks, and also to go into the sea and catch ﬁsh
for its proprietor. The following tale of a domesticated seal, mixed up with certain Irish super-
stitions, possesses a thrilling interest:</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r6" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="41" y="2034"/>
	<Point x="2153" y="2034"/>
	<Point x="2153" y="2514"/>
	<Point x="921" y="2516"/>
	<Point x="41" y="2514"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“About forty years ago, a young seal was taken in Clew Bay, and domesticated in the house of
a man whose house was situated on the sea-shore. It grew apace, became familiar with the
servants, and attached to the house and family; its habits were innocent and gentle; it played
with the children, came at its master's call, and, as the old man described it, was fond as a dog,
and playful as a kitten. Daily, the seal went out to ﬁsh, and, after providing for his own wants,
frequently brought in a salmon or a turbot for his master. His delight in the summer was to
bask in the sun, and in the winter to lie before the ﬁre; or, if permitted, to creep into the large
oven, which, at that time, formed the regular appendage of an Irish kitchen.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r7" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="56" y="2520"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="2520"/>
	<Point x="2146" y="3123"/>
	<Point x="658" y="3124"/>
	<Point x="56" y="3123"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“For four years the seal had been thus domesticated, when, unfortunately, a disease, called in
the country the crippawn—a kind of paralytic aﬀection of the limbs, which generally ends
fatally—attacked some black cattle belonging to the master of the house. Some died; others
became infected, and the customary cure, produced by changing them to clover pasture, failed.
A “Wise Woman” was consulted, and the hag assured the credulous owner that the mortality
among his cows was occasioned by having an unclean beast about his habitation—the harmless
and amusing seal. It must be made away with directly, or the crippawn would continue, and
her charms would be unable to arrest the malady. The superstitious wretch consented to the
hag's proposal; the seal was put on board a boat, carried out beyond Clare Island, and there com-
mitted to the deep to manage for himself as he best could.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r8" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="57" y="3125"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="3125"/>
	<Point x="2150" y="3545"/>
	<Point x="57" y="3545"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“The boat returned; the family retired to rest, and the next morning, the servant awakened
her master to tell him that the seal was quietly sleeping in the oven. The poor animal came
back over night to his beloved home, crept through an open window, and took possession of his
favorite resting-place. The next morning, another cow was reported to be unwell. The seal
must now be ﬁnally removed. A Galway ﬁshing-boat was leaving port on her return home,
and the master undertook to carry oﬀ the seal, and not put him overboard until he had gone
some leagues beyond Innis Boﬃn.</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion>
	<TextRegion id="r9" type="paragraph">
	<Coords>
	<Point x="112" y="3547"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="3547"/>
	<Point x="2148" y="3608"/>
	<Point x="112" y="3608"/></Coords>
	<TextEquiv>
	<PlainText></PlainText>
	<Unicode>“It was done—a day and night passed; the second evening closed; the servant was raking the</Unicode></TextEquiv></TextRegion></Page></PcGts>
